<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Computer on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/categories/computer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Computer on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:16:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/computer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hardware and Software 2013 I&amp;rsquo;m Most Thankful For</title>
      <link>/2013/11/29/the-hardware-and-software-2013-irsquom-most-thankful-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/29/the-hardware-and-software-2013-irsquom-most-thankful-for/</guid>
      <description>It’s time of year to give thanks. As a programmer, e-book reader, blog writer and web surfer, I should express my sincere appreciation to such hardware and software (I use majority of them at daily basis and most of them are free):
0. Hardware  Lenovo Thinkpad W520&amp;#160;(This is not free): my workhorse machine, now replaced by W530.
1. Google Stuff Google Chrome (Windows and Android apps): The first thing to do when getting a new machine is using IE to download the Chrome, then I can just keep moving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Utilities to Zip Files in Windows: Quick Notes</title>
      <link>/2013/06/29/free-utilities-to-zip-files-in-windows-quick-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 10:36:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/06/29/free-utilities-to-zip-files-in-windows-quick-notes/</guid>
      <description>1. Powershell cmdlet Write-Zip from PSCX Pro: flexible, easy to use
Con: relatively time consuming
2. 7-Zip Command-Line Pro: flexible, relatively quicker, easy to be embedded in other scripts
Con: (…)
3. Jar command in JDK Pro: flexible, relatively quicker, easy to be embedded in other scripts
Con: (…)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LearningR!</title>
      <link>/2013/02/08/learningr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 23:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/08/learningr/</guid>
      <description>I spent almost all of my blogging time last month to follow an online course in Coursera, Computing for Data Analysis (with R) by Dr. Roger&amp;#160; Peng of Johns Hopkins, Biostatistics Department. I already checked out bunch of Coursera courses just to take a look at what else MOOC look like, this R course was the first and only one I took seriously: I reviewed all slides (although didn’t watch the videos since I didn’t have enough time) and most important, finished all programming assignments(and got full score!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Jump into SAS Data Integration Studio</title>
      <link>/2013/01/12/how-to-jump-into-sas-data-integration-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/12/how-to-jump-into-sas-data-integration-studio/</guid>
      <description>This is for for SAS programmers who might be reluctant to check out a GUI tool like SAS Data Integration Studio (DIS for short, which is graphic tool to implement ETL processes: extract, transform, load). DIS translates all users dragged nodes, transformations and process into SAS codes which are traditionally written by SAS programmers. I find one of the benefits of using DIS is that I can package all the ETL work to other players(technical or nontechnical) then they can replay the job by dragging and clicking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Statistics: 2012</title>
      <link>/2013/01/01/blog-statistics-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 23:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/01/blog-statistics-2012/</guid>
      <description>(This blog’s page view data from Google Analytics; 43 posts in total in 2012)
Top 10 countries/territories and cities 
 Most of my readers come from US and I’m glad my Chinese fellows still fork me since I moved to US this year (today is my one year anniversary in US). To my surprising there are much more readers from South Korea than from Japan(#12) and Singapore(#22). Readers from a secret city (#7) are watching me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SAS Books: Shopping List 2012</title>
      <link>/2012/12/07/my-sas-books-shopping-list-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 23:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/07/my-sas-books-shopping-list-2012/</guid>
      <description>Last year I threw away all my SAS books (to friends and colleagues in Beijing) before moving to US. You might agree that it’s not economically bound to transport such heavy books intercontinentally! Now I just start to build my SAS library one by one. 
I will most probably not buy more SAS books as Christmas gifts for myself, so it’s time to take a 2012 snapshot of shopping:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract the Version of SAS and OS of a SAS Format or Macro Catalog: A Little Bit of Perl Regular Expression</title>
      <link>/2012/11/25/extract-the-version-of-sas-and-os-of-a-sas-format-or-macro-catalog-a-little-bit-of-perl-regular-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 20:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/25/extract-the-version-of-sas-and-os-of-a-sas-format-or-macro-catalog-a-little-bit-of-perl-regular-expression/</guid>
      <description>SAS Sample 34444(Determine the operating system in which a format catalog was created) posts piece of codes to get the version of SAS and OS of a SAS format catalog. It is useful since a SAS catalog can be only read in the operating systems same to its source machine.
2 cents add to this note:
First, we do not need to write codes to get to know the machine version for a catalog(formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress and Black Friday</title>
      <link>/2012/11/23/wordpress-and-black-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 23:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/23/wordpress-and-black-friday/</guid>
      <description>Yes it’s BLACK that today this WordPress based blog was down for a while with a 500 error:
 The website encountered an error while retrieving http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/. It may be down for maintenance or configured incorrectly.
 I checked web log and it says:
 [24-Nov-2012 02:58:49] PHP Parse error:&amp;#160; syntax error, unexpected T_STRING, expecting &amp;#8216;,&amp;#8217; or &amp;#8216;;&amp;#8217; in ../public_html/jiangtanghu/blog/wp-content/plugins/wp-conditional-captcha/wp-conditional-captcha.php on line 401
 So the problem comes from a WordPress plugin “Conditional CAPTCHA for WordPress” .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Your Own SAS Admin: Create Customized SAS Sessions</title>
      <link>/2012/10/18/be-your-own-sas-admin-create-customized-sas-sessions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Oct 2012 19:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/18/be-your-own-sas-admin-create-customized-sas-sessions/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;

You may find such SAS desktop shortcuts useful:
 click icon A then you get a SAS session titled “Project A” (you may notice your SAS session with title “SAS” by default). In this session, the current working folder is just where you put Project A (the default may be like C:usersyourID). Also, some autoexec codes run including libname, fileref, formats search, macro loading and other customized options/settings.  Keep session A alive, then click icon B: you get your SAS session specified for Project B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS Perl Regular Expression (PRX) Talk in the forthcoming SESUG 2012</title>
      <link>/2012/10/11/sas-perl-regular-expression-prx-talk-in-the-forthcoming-sesug-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2012 21:20:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/11/sas-perl-regular-expression-prx-talk-in-the-forthcoming-sesug-2012/</guid>
      <description>Research Triangle will host SouthEast SAS Users Group (SESUG) 2012 conference (October 14-16, Sheraton Imperial Hotel, Durham, NC; back to the home of SAS!). It will be my first regional SAS user conference and I will have a talk on SAS Perl Regular Expression(PRX), in the morning of next Monday, Oct 15.

SAS PRX is an old school topic somehow. After dumping the paper, I think I should restructure my talk in a more accessible way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Powershell: Up to v3.0</title>
      <link>/2012/10/08/powershell-up-to-v3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2012 22:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/08/powershell-up-to-v3.0/</guid>
      <description>Just update Windows Powershell to version 3.0 and I do like this new GUI (Integrated Scripting Environment, ISE) with a console, a script window and a command list (Powershell is a true Windows shell; you may try to type 1+2 in the old CMD console!):

I also used a free Powershell GUI product, PowerGUI with similar interface like ISE. The latest PowerGUI (3.2.0.2237) supports Powershell 2.0 by default (while you can force it to play with PS 3.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>