<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GIThub on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GIThub on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 15:59:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS ODS Tagsets Guru Eric Gebhart on Github</title>
      <link>/2013/09/17/sas-ods-tagsets-guru-eric-gebhart-on-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2013 15:59:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/17/sas-ods-tagsets-guru-eric-gebhart-on-github/</guid>
      <description>Check it out:
 https://github.com/EricGebhart
 Also, his homepage:
 http://ericgebhart.com/
 Shameless Ad: I will have a talk on Github for SAS programmers in the forthcoming SESUG (Oct 20-23, 2013) at St.Pete Beach, FL. Welcome to drop by if you are on the spot!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>List Processing With SAS: A Github Repository</title>
      <link>/2013/03/31/list-processing-with-sas-a-github-repository/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2013 22:24:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/03/31/list-processing-with-sas-a-github-repository/</guid>
      <description>I have a function like macro (recursive version) to create a sequence:
 %macro _list(n,pre=ff);
%if &amp;amp;n=1 %then &amp;amp;pre.1;
%else %_list(%eval(&amp;amp;n-1)),&amp;amp;pre.&amp;n;
%mend _list;
%put %_list(3); *produces ff1, ff2, ff3;
 But when I read one of Ian Whitlock’s papers, Names, Names, Names &amp;#8211; Make Me a List (SGF 2007, SESUG 2008), I say: stop! I&amp;#8217;m gonna use Ian’s %range and I create Github page to hold it (with minimum modifications due to personal preference).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github for Clinical/Statistical Programmers</title>
      <link>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</guid>
      <description>PhUSE-FDA Working Group 5 (Development of Standard Scripts for Analysis and Programming) just adopted Google Code as collaborative programming platform. Google Code is one of the most popular and respected open source software hosting sites in the world and it is definitely a good choice for PhUSE-FDA WG5.
But after viewing one of WG5’s working reports, Sharing Standard Statistical Scripts and getting to know why they finally chose Google Code (rather than Github which was also tested by WG5 members), I think it’s necessary to clarify some misunderstanding against Github where I’m also an occasional user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WordPress and Black Friday</title>
      <link>/2012/11/23/wordpress-and-black-friday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 23:04:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/23/wordpress-and-black-friday/</guid>
      <description>Yes it’s BLACK that today this WordPress based blog was down for a while with a 500 error:
 The website encountered an error while retrieving http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/. It may be down for maintenance or configured incorrectly.
 I checked web log and it says:
 [24-Nov-2012 02:58:49] PHP Parse error:&amp;#160; syntax error, unexpected T_STRING, expecting &amp;#8216;,&amp;#8217; or &amp;#8216;;&amp;#8217; in ../public_html/jiangtanghu/blog/wp-content/plugins/wp-conditional-captcha/wp-conditional-captcha.php on line 401
 So the problem comes from a WordPress plugin “Conditional CAPTCHA for WordPress” .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There Any Better Way? Publishing Process For CDISC Standards Documentation</title>
      <link>/2012/07/19/is-there-any-better-way-publishing-process-for-cdisc-standards-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 01:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/19/is-there-any-better-way-publishing-process-for-cdisc-standards-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#160; 1. The Pain I read from Lex Jansen (@LexJansen) that CDISC SDTM v1.3 and SDTMIG v3.1.3 were newly released. It’s pretty nice since CDISC SDTM was supposed to be released semiannually in the new publishing cycle. We can see the team put great efforts on this new version, but frankly speaking, this delivery (the way to display, not the content itself) is far away elegant.
The new SDTM Implementation Guide (IG) v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitHub and Weekend Programming</title>
      <link>/2012/02/19/github-and-weekend-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2012 16:17:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/02/19/github-and-weekend-programming/</guid>
      <description>Yihui of Iowa State just texted me that GitHub is programmers’ Facebook. Inspired by him(great thanks!), I also begin to play with GitHub now:
 https://github.com/Jiangtang
 Currently I only created one repo as personal SAS code repository. To kill weekend time, I uploaded piece of codes to count the OpenCDISC validation rules by models. To use it:
 filename CDISC url “https://raw.github.com/Jiangtang/Programming-SAS/master/Rules_Count_OpenCDISC_XML.sas”;
%include CDISC;
%Rules_Count_OpenCDISC_XML(dir=C:tempOpenCDISCsoftwareopencdisc-validatorconfig)
 while get:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>