<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PROC FREQ on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/proc-freq/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PROC FREQ on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 22:59:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/proc-freq/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Noninferiority Testing with SAS</title>
      <link>/2013/08/26/noninferiority-testing-with-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 22:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/26/noninferiority-testing-with-sas/</guid>
      <description>I planed to extend nonWinferiority testing to one of my statistical notes,&amp;#160; Equivalence Testing and TOST (Two One-Sided Test) since noninferiority test is simply half part of the equivalence test. Today I’m glad to find an even better explanation from
 SAS Usage Note 48616: Design and analysis of noninferiority studies
 You will love it if you are interested in this subject (bookmark this link since it looks like unfinished somehow).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of SAS: A Personal Nomination 2012</title>
      <link>/2012/12/31/best-of-sas-a-personal-nomination-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 01:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/31/best-of-sas-a-personal-nomination-2012/</guid>
      <description>There SAS applications/procedures/features were not necessarily available since 2012. This year I paid special attention to them when began to use SAS 9.3. The following notes are&amp;#160; totally my personal endorsement purely based my own experience as a user:
XML File Reading: SAS XML Mapper 
SAS XML Mapper itself is not an elegant tool from software design perspective (an example: I keep multiple versions because the latest version seems not carry out all the functionalities from old ones), but it is best XML file processing tool for SAS programmers like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (5): Confidence Intervals for Difference Between Independent Binomial Proportions Using SAS</title>
      <link>/2012/09/23/statistical-notes-5-confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-using-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 21:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/23/statistical-notes-5-confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-using-sas/</guid>
      <description>A guy notices a bunch of targets scattered over a barn wall, and in the center of each, in the &amp;ldquo;bulls-eye,&amp;rdquo; is a bullet hole. &amp;ldquo;Wow,&amp;rdquo; he says to the farmer, &amp;ldquo;that&amp;#8217;s pretty good shooting. How&amp;#8217;d you do it?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Oh,&amp;rdquo; says the farmer, &amp;ldquo;it was easy. I painted the targets after I shot the holes.&amp;rdquo; – An Old Joke
 Note on how to get the difference between independent binomial proportions using SAS PROC FREQ (tested in SAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequentist or Baysian in A Binomial Test</title>
      <link>/2012/09/21/frequentist-or-baysian-in-a-binomial-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 01:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/21/frequentist-or-baysian-in-a-binomial-test/</guid>
      <description>A latest updated post on Freakonomics, Beware the Weasel Word “Statistical” in Statistical Significance!,&amp;#160; seemed to attempt to challenge frequentist statistics by Bayesian. I have no research on Bayesian and won’t jump to the debates. I’d rather to use this case to apply the Dragon’s Teeth and Fleas logic of hypothesis testing (at least I think frequentist is pretty intuitive). 
A story goes with this post, that Bob won 20 times out of total 30 rounds with Alice in a children card game, “War”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (3): Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion Using SAS</title>
      <link>/2012/09/15/statistical-notes-3-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/15/statistical-notes-3-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas/</guid>
      <description>A guy notices a bunch of targets scattered over a barn wall, and in the center of each, in the &amp;#8220;bulls-eye,&amp;#8221; is a bullet hole. &amp;#8220;Wow,&amp;#8221; he says to the farmer, &amp;#8220;that&amp;#8217;s pretty good shooting. How&amp;#8217;d you do it?&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Oh,&amp;#8221; says the farmer, &amp;#8220;it was easy. I painted the targets after I shot the holes.&amp;#8221; – An Old Joke
 Last year I dumped piece of SAS codes to compute confidence intervals for single proportion using 11 methods including 7 presented by one of Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>