<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAS Data Integration Studio on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/sas-data-integration-studio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAS Data Integration Studio on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 18:08:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sas-data-integration-studio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Jump into SAS Data Integration Studio</title>
      <link>/2013/01/12/how-to-jump-into-sas-data-integration-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/12/how-to-jump-into-sas-data-integration-studio/</guid>
      <description>This is for for SAS programmers who might be reluctant to check out a GUI tool like SAS Data Integration Studio (DIS for short, which is graphic tool to implement ETL processes: extract, transform, load). DIS translates all users dragged nodes, transformations and process into SAS codes which are traditionally written by SAS programmers. I find one of the benefits of using DIS is that I can package all the ETL work to other players(technical or nontechnical) then they can replay the job by dragging and clicking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS Certified, Again</title>
      <link>/2012/12/22/sas-certified-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 23:13:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/22/sas-certified-again/</guid>
      <description>Last week I got another SAS certification, SAS Certified Data Integration Developer for SAS 9 and I must say it can’t be better as a SAS holiday gift for myself!
I took all my SAS certificates when employed (when in Sanofi Pasteur, 2010, I got two SAS programming certificates, Base and Advanced). You may say it’s kind of certificate for sake of certificate and not for applying a job like college students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macro Quoting in SAS Data Integration Studio</title>
      <link>/2012/11/19/macro-quoting-in-sas-data-integration-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 21:35:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/19/macro-quoting-in-sas-data-integration-studio/</guid>
      <description>You can run the following piece of codes successfully in these 3 SAS programming environments:
 BASE SAS  Enterprise Guide: create a new “File-New-Program”  SAS Data Integration Studio: create a new “Tool-Code Editor”    %let species=&amp;ldquo;Setosa&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Versicolor&amp;rdquo;;
data a; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; set sashelp.iris; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; where species in (&amp;amp;species); run; 

 Then create a Transformation in SAS Data Integration Studio (DIS for short; I use version 4.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>