<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Database on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/categories/database/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Database on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 21:31:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/database/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Map and Reduce in MapReduce: a SAS Illustration</title>
      <link>/2011/10/04/map-and-reduce-in-mapreduce-a-sas-illustration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 21:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/10/04/map-and-reduce-in-mapreduce-a-sas-illustration/</guid>
      <description>In last post, I mentioned Hadoop, the open source implementation of Google’s MapReduce for parallelized processing of big data. In this long National Holiday, I read the original Google paper, _MapReduce: Simplified Data Processing on Large Clusters_ by Jeffrey Dean and Sanjay Ghemawat and got that the terminologies of “map” and “reduce” were basically borrowed from Lisp, an old functional language that I even didn’t play “hello world” with. For Python users, the idea of Map and Reduce is also very straightforward because the workhorse data structure in Python is just the list, a sequence of values that you can just imagine that they are the nodes(clusters, chunk servers, …) in a distributed system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analytical Valley: Big Data and Data Scientists (and SAS Programmers)</title>
      <link>/2011/09/14/an-analytical-valley-big-data-and-data-scientists-and-sas-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 22:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/14/an-analytical-valley-big-data-and-data-scientists-and-sas-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Tom Davenport reported an observation that Silicon Valley is becoming more analytical since companies in the Valley such as Google, Facebook, eBay, LinkedLn all have strong presences in analytics. Besides such predominant companies, I’d also like to add Yahoo to the list although Yahoo is no longer in its peak. Yahoo is the largest sponsor and contributor of Hadoop, an open source framework for distributed processing of so called “big data”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is Alfred?</title>
      <link>/2011/08/31/who-is-alfred/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 22:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/31/who-is-alfred/</guid>
      <description>Tell me something about Alfred, male or female? age? height and weight?
 Oracle database (version 9 and below) had a well known default demo account SCOTT with a password, TIGER (and TIGER was the name of the real person Bruce Scott ’s cat, see) and in this account, there are some tables named DEPT, EMP, BONUS and SALGRADE (you can read their meaning). Almost every Oracle DBA learn SQL using these database and an joke just says that in DBA’s meetings, people just&amp;#160; warm up saying “how about Smith?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work With Oracle: A Quick Sheet for SAS Programmers</title>
      <link>/2009/12/04/work-with-oracle-a-quick-sheet-for-sas-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 09:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/12/04/work-with-oracle-a-quick-sheet-for-sas-programmers/</guid>
      <description>(Note: All the followings are tested on Windows XP environment.)
0. Install Oracle Database 10g Express Edition
Fast (and free) to download, easy to deploy and simple to admin&amp;#8211;for learning and testing purpose, Oracle Database 10g Express Edition (Oracle Database XE, a mini version of Oracle Database 10g Release 2) are strongly recommended:
0.1 Download it at its homepage(206MB);
0.2 Install it following default settings;
0.3 Unlock accounts for HR and SCOTT.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>