<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metadata on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/metadata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Metadata on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 21:46:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/metadata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>New Game in Town: SAS Metadata Administration</title>
      <link>/2013/03/13/new-game-in-town-sas-metadata-administration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2013 21:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/03/13/new-game-in-town-sas-metadata-administration/</guid>
      <description>You might also read that there were constant (although still not frequent) posts on SAS metadata querying and other administration tasks in SAS blogosphere since 2012 (when I started to play with it^). It is yet another evidence that more and more SAS programmers switched from SAS foundation to the so called SAS intelligent platform. In the traditional SAS foundation world, a nice source of metadata is the Dictionary table (or V datasets in SASHELP library); In SAS intelligent platform, a much more comprehensive metadata is stored in a SAS Metadata Server (Is &amp;#8220;Data&amp;#8221; singular or plural?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of SAS: A Personal Nomination 2012</title>
      <link>/2012/12/31/best-of-sas-a-personal-nomination-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 01:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/31/best-of-sas-a-personal-nomination-2012/</guid>
      <description>There SAS applications/procedures/features were not necessarily available since 2012. This year I paid special attention to them when began to use SAS 9.3. The following notes are&amp;#160; totally my personal endorsement purely based my own experience as a user:
XML File Reading: SAS XML Mapper 
SAS XML Mapper itself is not an elegant tool from software design perspective (an example: I keep multiple versions because the latest version seems not carry out all the functionalities from old ones), but it is best XML file processing tool for SAS programmers like me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>