<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQL on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/sql/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQL on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 23:37:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>LearningR!</title>
      <link>/2013/02/08/learningr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 23:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/08/learningr/</guid>
      <description>I spent almost all of my blogging time last month to follow an online course in Coursera, Computing for Data Analysis (with R) by Dr. Roger&amp;#160; Peng of Johns Hopkins, Biostatistics Department. I already checked out bunch of Coursera courses just to take a look at what else MOOC look like, this R course was the first and only one I took seriously: I reviewed all slides (although didn’t watch the videos since I didn’t have enough time) and most important, finished all programming assignments(and got full score!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Jump into SAS Data Integration Studio</title>
      <link>/2013/01/12/how-to-jump-into-sas-data-integration-studio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2013 18:08:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/12/how-to-jump-into-sas-data-integration-studio/</guid>
      <description>This is for for SAS programmers who might be reluctant to check out a GUI tool like SAS Data Integration Studio (DIS for short, which is graphic tool to implement ETL processes: extract, transform, load). DIS translates all users dragged nodes, transformations and process into SAS codes which are traditionally written by SAS programmers. I find one of the benefits of using DIS is that I can package all the ETL work to other players(technical or nontechnical) then they can replay the job by dragging and clicking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Get Row Numbers in SAS Proc SQL (and DO NOT Use the Undocumented MONOTONIC Function)</title>
      <link>/2013/01/11/how-to-get-row-numbers-in-sas-proc-sql-and-do-not-use-the-undocumented-monotonic-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Jan 2013 15:01:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/11/how-to-get-row-numbers-in-sas-proc-sql-and-do-not-use-the-undocumented-monotonic-function/</guid>
      <description>SAS programmers are longing for row number function used in Proc SQL, like ROW_NUMBER() in Oracle SQL and it will act like data step system variable N. When you google this question, most likely you will get MONOTONIC() function, which might be one of the most famous undocumented features shipped by SAS. You can of course use it, but at your own risk! In SAS Usage Note 15138, it&amp;#8217;s said:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analytical Valley: Big Data and Data Scientists (and SAS Programmers)</title>
      <link>/2011/09/14/an-analytical-valley-big-data-and-data-scientists-and-sas-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 22:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/14/an-analytical-valley-big-data-and-data-scientists-and-sas-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Tom Davenport reported an observation that Silicon Valley is becoming more analytical since companies in the Valley such as Google, Facebook, eBay, LinkedLn all have strong presences in analytics. Besides such predominant companies, I’d also like to add Yahoo to the list although Yahoo is no longer in its peak. Yahoo is the largest sponsor and contributor of Hadoop, an open source framework for distributed processing of so called “big data”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work With Oracle: A Quick Sheet for SAS Programmers</title>
      <link>/2009/12/04/work-with-oracle-a-quick-sheet-for-sas-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2009 09:33:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/12/04/work-with-oracle-a-quick-sheet-for-sas-programmers/</guid>
      <description>(Note: All the followings are tested on Windows XP environment.)
0. Install Oracle Database 10g Express Edition
Fast (and free) to download, easy to deploy and simple to admin&amp;#8211;for learning and testing purpose, Oracle Database 10g Express Edition (Oracle Database XE, a mini version of Oracle Database 10g Release 2) are strongly recommended:
0.1 Download it at its homepage(206MB);
0.2 Install it following default settings;
0.3 Unlock accounts for HR and SCOTT.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>