<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 22:05:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (3B): Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion Using SAS, Updated</title>
      <link>/2015/05/22/statistical-notes-3b-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 22:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/22/statistical-notes-3b-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas-updated/</guid>
      <description>This quick note serves as a supplementnote of my previous Statistical Notes (3): Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion Using SAS which I will extend as a SESUG 2015 paper. Basically I added a new Blaker method to my CI_Single_Proportion.sas file and found more CIs from SAS PROC FREQ.
First of all, call the script:
 filename CI url “https://raw.github.com/Jiangtang/Programming-SAS/master/CI_Single_Proportion.sas” ; %include CI;
%CI_Single_Proportion(r=81,n=263);
 and the output:

The #12 is the one newly added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating Covariance by SAS, A Brutal Way</title>
      <link>/2015/05/12/calculating-covariance-by-sas-a-brutal-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 15:56:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/12/calculating-covariance-by-sas-a-brutal-way/</guid>
      <description>It was very disappointed that there is only one built-in method to calculate covariance in Base SAS: that’s in PROC CORR (while you can also do it in SAS/IML, of course):

The following is a quick-and-dirty way to get a function like %COV:
 %macro COV(data, var1,var2); &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; %local _cov; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; %let rc = %sysfunc(dosubl(%str(
&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; ods select none ; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; ods output cov=_cov;
&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; proc corr data=&amp;amp;data&amp;#160; cov ; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; var &amp;amp;var1 &amp;amp;var2 ; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; run;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion (Again): A Quick Note</title>
      <link>/2015/05/05/confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-again-a-quick-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2015 14:22:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/05/confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-again-a-quick-note/</guid>
      <description>In Lex’s library of the latest SAS Global Forum 2015 papers, I found an interesting paper by Wu Gong, Jeffreys Interval for One-Sample Proportion with SAS/STAT Software, where SAS MCMC procedure and a so called Random Walk Metropolis Algorithm were implemented to calculate the Jeffreys interval for binomial proportion.
Years ago I wrote several posts on this topic:
 Statistical Notes (3): Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion Using SAS
Statistical Notes (5): Confidence Intervals for Difference Between Independent Binomial Proportions Using SAS</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Contributors to SAS/STAT</title>
      <link>/2013/09/18/community-contributors-to-sas/stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 19:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/18/community-contributors-to-sas/stat/</guid>
      <description>I suppose it is tempting, if the only tool you have is a hammer, to treat everything as if it were a nail. &amp;#8211; Abraham Maslow, The Psychology of Science, 1966
 Yes it’s true: since I have a pretty rich collection of SAS list processing macros, I’d like my list container to hold everything itemized. Here is a nail I found in SAS/STAT online help.
There are strong community contributing to the development of SAS/STAT software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noninferiority Testing with SAS</title>
      <link>/2013/08/26/noninferiority-testing-with-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 22:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/26/noninferiority-testing-with-sas/</guid>
      <description>I planed to extend nonWinferiority testing to one of my statistical notes,&amp;#160; Equivalence Testing and TOST (Two One-Sided Test) since noninferiority test is simply half part of the equivalence test. Today I’m glad to find an even better explanation from
 SAS Usage Note 48616: Design and analysis of noninferiority studies
 You will love it if you are interested in this subject (bookmark this link since it looks like unfinished somehow).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidence Intervals for Difference Between Independent Binomial Proportions: A SAS 9.4/STAT 12.3 Update</title>
      <link>/2013/08/25/confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 23:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/25/confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</guid>
      <description>For the computing of confidence intervals for difference between two independent binomial proportions in SAS 9.4/STAT 12.3, it’s hard to figure out exactly how many methods are available because there is no “CL=ALL” trigger in RISKDIFF option (but you can get one in BIONOMIAL option to compute the confidence intervals for binomial proportion). As far as I hacked, I got 11 intervals (last year I tried SAS 9.3 and got 8; codes available below):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion: A SAS 9.4/STAT 12.3 Update</title>
      <link>/2013/08/22/confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 10:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/22/confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</guid>
      <description>1. A new confidence limits method added, Wilson (Corrected) 2. The binomialc option is no longer documented, but still works        After getting the access to SAS 9.4 alone with SAS/STAT 12.3, I first took a look at my favorite SAS statistical procedure, PROF FREQ.&amp;#160; Last year I had a note on confidence intervals for binomial proportion based on SAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SAS Books: Shopping List 2012</title>
      <link>/2012/12/07/my-sas-books-shopping-list-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 23:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/07/my-sas-books-shopping-list-2012/</guid>
      <description>Last year I threw away all my SAS books (to friends and colleagues in Beijing) before moving to US. You might agree that it’s not economically bound to transport such heavy books intercontinentally! Now I just start to build my SAS library one by one. 
I will most probably not buy more SAS books as Christmas gifts for myself, so it’s time to take a 2012 snapshot of shopping:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (5): Confidence Intervals for Difference Between Independent Binomial Proportions Using SAS</title>
      <link>/2012/09/23/statistical-notes-5-confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-using-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 21:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/23/statistical-notes-5-confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-using-sas/</guid>
      <description>A guy notices a bunch of targets scattered over a barn wall, and in the center of each, in the &amp;ldquo;bulls-eye,&amp;rdquo; is a bullet hole. &amp;ldquo;Wow,&amp;rdquo; he says to the farmer, &amp;ldquo;that&amp;#8217;s pretty good shooting. How&amp;#8217;d you do it?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Oh,&amp;rdquo; says the farmer, &amp;ldquo;it was easy. I painted the targets after I shot the holes.&amp;rdquo; – An Old Joke
 Note on how to get the difference between independent binomial proportions using SAS PROC FREQ (tested in SAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Book on Confidence Intervals for Proportions by Prof. Newcombe</title>
      <link>/2012/09/21/new-book-on-confidence-intervals-for-proportions-by-prof.-newcombe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 21:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/21/new-book-on-confidence-intervals-for-proportions-by-prof.-newcombe/</guid>
      <description>Check it out: a new book on confidence intervals for proportions by Prof. Robert G. Newcombe&amp;#160; just recently available from CRC Press:

 Confidence Intervals for Proportions and Related Measures of Effect Size
 This book also supplies a set of Excel spreadsheets to calculating CIs, see
 http://www.crcpress.com/product/isbn/9781439812785
 Other users may be interested on a SAS or R implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequentist or Baysian in A Binomial Test</title>
      <link>/2012/09/21/frequentist-or-baysian-in-a-binomial-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 01:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/21/frequentist-or-baysian-in-a-binomial-test/</guid>
      <description>A latest updated post on Freakonomics, Beware the Weasel Word “Statistical” in Statistical Significance!,&amp;#160; seemed to attempt to challenge frequentist statistics by Bayesian. I have no research on Bayesian and won’t jump to the debates. I’d rather to use this case to apply the Dragon’s Teeth and Fleas logic of hypothesis testing (at least I think frequentist is pretty intuitive). 
A story goes with this post, that Bob won 20 times out of total 30 rounds with Alice in a children card game, “War”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (4): Dragon&amp;rsquo;s Teeth and Fleas: Hypothesis Testing in Plain English</title>
      <link>/2012/09/16/statistical-notes-4-dragonrsquos-teeth-and-fleas-hypothesis-testing-in-plain-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 14:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/16/statistical-notes-4-dragonrsquos-teeth-and-fleas-hypothesis-testing-in-plain-english/</guid>
      <description>Statisticians aren’t the problem for data science. The real problem is too many posers &amp;#8212; Cathy O’Neil
you actually do need to understand how to invert a matrix at some point in your life if you want to be a data scientist. &amp;#8212; Cathy O’Neil
 
I was asked in several different occasions to explain hypothesis testing to non-technical people in plain English. Now I think I got a pretty neat one while honors belong to three great Germans, Friedrich Engels, Karl Marx, and Heinrich Heine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (3): Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion Using SAS</title>
      <link>/2012/09/15/statistical-notes-3-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/15/statistical-notes-3-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas/</guid>
      <description>A guy notices a bunch of targets scattered over a barn wall, and in the center of each, in the &amp;#8220;bulls-eye,&amp;#8221; is a bullet hole. &amp;#8220;Wow,&amp;#8221; he says to the farmer, &amp;#8220;that&amp;#8217;s pretty good shooting. How&amp;#8217;d you do it?&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Oh,&amp;#8221; says the farmer, &amp;#8220;it was easy. I painted the targets after I shot the holes.&amp;#8221; – An Old Joke
 Last year I dumped piece of SAS codes to compute confidence intervals for single proportion using 11 methods including 7 presented by one of Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (2): Equivalence Testing and TOST (Two One-Sided Test)</title>
      <link>/2012/09/12/statistical-notes-2-equivalence-testing-and-tost-two-one-sided-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 22:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/12/statistical-notes-2-equivalence-testing-and-tost-two-one-sided-test/</guid>
      <description>_Programmers Need to Learn Statistics Or I will Kill Them All –Zed A. Shaw_
 In an equivalence testing&amp;#160;example against lognormal data,&amp;#160; a TOST (Two One-Sided Test)&amp;#160; option used in SAS TTEST procedure:
 proc ttest data=auc dist=lognormal tost(0.8, 1.25); &amp;#160;&amp;#160; paired TestAUC*RefAUC; run;
 And the output:

Since the 90% (who not 95%? see below) limit of the geometric mean ratio (0.9412) , [0.8634,1.0260], lies in the FDA endorsed equivalence bounds [0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (1): Geometric Mean and Geometric Mean Ratio</title>
      <link>/2012/09/12/statistical-notes-1-geometric-mean-and-geometric-mean-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 20:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/12/statistical-notes-1-geometric-mean-and-geometric-mean-ratio/</guid>
      <description>_Programmers Need to Learn Statistics Or I will Kill Them All –Zed A. Shaw_
 Just read since SAS 9.2, the TTEST procedure also natively supports Equivalence Test by simply adding a TOST option (Two one-sided tests). In a example, TTEST procedure reports a geometric mean as 0.9412, which is the geometric mean of a ratio, TestAUC/RefAUC. It can also be calculated manually by
 proc sql; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; select exp(mean(log(TestAUC/RefAUC))) &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;ldquo;geometric mean of TestAUC/RefAUC&amp;rdquo; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; from auc; quit;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On three statistical realms</title>
      <link>/2010/10/06/on-three-statistical-realms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 11:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/10/06/on-three-statistical-realms/</guid>
      <description>Peter Petocz and Anna Reid(2010) grouped three levels of students’ conceptions of statistics:
 Level I:&amp;#160;&amp;#160; focus on techniques Level II:&amp;#160; focus on using data Level III: focus on meaning  I found the three conceptions could be easily interpreted as the three kinds of state of learning and using statistics based on my personal experience:
 State I: focus on techniques—As a student of Economics and (then) Software Engineering, I needed some statistics techniques to support my study on data mining and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>