<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAS 9.4 on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/sas-9.4/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAS 9.4 on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 12:48:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sas-9.4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Use SAS?</title>
      <link>/2013/09/16/how-i-use-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2013 12:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/16/how-i-use-sas/</guid>
      <description>It’s pretty fun to read SAS/Graph expert Robert Allison’s note, Using SAS- A Case Study on his SAS programming environment, such as SAS version, OS, fileserver and editors. Here is my follow up:
SAS Version I always want to keep pace with the latest SAS software; something I got it, sometime not. As of September 2013, I use SAS 9.4 in my workstation.
For different tasks, clients or their combinations, I should use specific versions of SAS in customers’ computing environment remotely or in virtual machines; they are mostly SAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidence Intervals for Difference Between Independent Binomial Proportions: A SAS 9.4/STAT 12.3 Update</title>
      <link>/2013/08/25/confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 23:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/25/confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</guid>
      <description>For the computing of confidence intervals for difference between two independent binomial proportions in SAS 9.4/STAT 12.3, it’s hard to figure out exactly how many methods are available because there is no “CL=ALL” trigger in RISKDIFF option (but you can get one in BIONOMIAL option to compute the confidence intervals for binomial proportion). As far as I hacked, I got 11 intervals (last year I tried SAS 9.3 and got 8; codes available below):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion: A SAS 9.4/STAT 12.3 Update</title>
      <link>/2013/08/22/confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 10:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/22/confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</guid>
      <description>1. A new confidence limits method added, Wilson (Corrected) 2. The binomialc option is no longer documented, but still works        After getting the access to SAS 9.4 alone with SAS/STAT 12.3, I first took a look at my favorite SAS statistical procedure, PROF FREQ.&amp;#160; Last year I had a note on confidence intervals for binomial proportion based on SAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Good Morning, Hotfix Tool for SAS 9.4</title>
      <link>/2013/07/29/good-morning-hotfix-tool-for-sas-9.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2013 09:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/29/good-morning-hotfix-tool-for-sas-9.4/</guid>
      <description>The first news I got from today’s inbox is that SAS Hot Fix Analysis Download and Deployment Tool (SASHFADD) for SAS 9.4 is released today.&amp;#160; Just yesterday I found it was not available.
I did a quick launching and it works fine. Check it out:
http://ftp.sas.com/techsup/download/hotfix/HF2/SASHFADD.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Box: SAS 9.4 in Windows 7</title>
      <link>/2013/07/28/open-box-sas-9.4-in-windows-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 16:06:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/28/open-box-sas-9.4-in-windows-7/</guid>
      <description>That’s a record in my personal SAS software adoption: SAS 9.4 was released at 10 July 2013 and I just got it installed two weeks later! 
Here my first-day notes with SAS 9.4:
1. SAS Foundation 9.4 can be co-existed with SAS 9.3. If SAS 9.3 was already installed, the default of path of 9.4 is C:\Program Files\SASHome2; otherwise, it will take over C:\Program Files\SASHome.
2. But for SAS PC Files Server 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catch Up with SAS</title>
      <link>/2013/07/11/catch-up-with-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2013 00:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/07/11/catch-up-with-sas/</guid>
      <description>SAS 9.3 was released at July 2011 when I former company just successfully launched an upgrading to&amp;#160; SAS 9.2.&amp;#160; SAS 9.2 came to life at March 2008 (it’s a big leap) and at that time I played with SAS 9.1.3 heavily. Yesterday(10Jul2013) was the official release day for SAS 9.4 while I just got my SAS 9.3 installed at this March!
Based on historical data, I will probably play with SAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>