<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adjective on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/adjective/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adjective on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="/tags/adjective/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ADJECTIVE Encounters</title>
      <link>/2011/07/02/adjective-encounters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 10:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/02/adjective-encounters/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really she is the strangest creature in the world, far from heroic, variable as a weathercock, “&lt;strong&gt;bashful, insolent; chaste, lustful; prating, silent; laborious, delicate; ingenious, heavy; melancholic, pleasant; lying, true; knowing, ignorant; liberal, covetous, and prodigal&lt;/strong&gt;”— in short, so complex, so indefinite, …&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;#8211;Virginia Woolf, &lt;em&gt;The Common Reader&lt;/em&gt;, First Series (1925)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t know if Ernest Hemingway is still one of the recognized dominant writers in colleges English education. At least once&amp;#160; a time he WAS. In an extreme form, he used only nouns and verbs to construct sentences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my personal English education(as Second Language), admittedly that there is also an absence of adjectives. It is just wonderful, nice, great, cool, weird, awesome,&amp;#160; and all in all, everything is OK or not OK, good or not good. In writing, my sentences lack of tone and shades. I write only technical articles in English and people can often well manage the so-called technical borings when acquiring information, knowledge, and opinions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In reading when I try to just read for the sake of reading itself, I also find it is difficult to dig into pure literature pages where rich adjectives assembled heavily. I only read smoothly technical papers. So when I happened to have a paper book of Woolf and also loaded a corresponding public domain e-book in Kindle, I read the most intensive instances of adjectives ever. It is really totally different experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There would be three types in any languages. For English:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in the top, pure literature, Shakespeare-like;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;middle, which could be called the universal or international English; it is be the dominate English among nations in business, technology and even academia; most of the popular writers also utilize such sort of English to extent their global reputation;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bottom, the street language, slangs, talk-show.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I penetrate the English through the middle like almost all of the ESL learners. It is the most convenient and effective way in a very short run. But for a leap in long run, some friends just suggest that I should go down the street or climb up to the top. Ok I am on the way. Virginia Woolf is the first stop and I keep the first notes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>