<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data mining on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/categories/data-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data mining on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/data-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Lost Time: 2016</title>
      <link>/2017/05/04/in-search-of-lost-time-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/04/in-search-of-lost-time-2016/</guid>
      <description>2016 was gone, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even leave one single blog post. An obvious inference should be, 2016 doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;hellip;
2016 was a year of struggle for me as a SAS programmer. I earn my bread mostly using SAS, but is a SAS programmer like me cool? It&amp;rsquo;s not a silly question. Lots of SAS programmers feel the crunch.
So, in 2016, I
 learned some Python, attended Pydata Carolinas, learned some Spark, and got certified by edX somehow with all the bubble words in the title, Distributed Machine Learning with Apache Spark, learned some math, Linear Algebra, learned more math, Probability, learned even more math, Numerical Analysis, and didn&amp;rsquo;t update one single blog post, because all my spare time and coffee making time were simply run out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Clips: Data Scientist Episode II</title>
      <link>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 15:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</guid>
      <description>1. What is A Data Scientist Anyway?

2. You Just Can’t Be Replaced by Yourselves!

3. We are all Data Scientists!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Clip: Data Scientist</title>
      <link>/2012/11/30/weekend-clip-data-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 22:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/30/weekend-clip-data-scientist/</guid>
      <description>Two tweets: 

One blog post: _Statisticians aren’t the problem for data science. The real problem is too many posers_
One job advertisement: SAS Data Scientist ?(!)
A joke: The biggest joke about data scientist is that the Google query “data scientist joke” returns nothing interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Map and Reduce in MapReduce: a SAS Illustration</title>
      <link>/2011/10/04/map-and-reduce-in-mapreduce-a-sas-illustration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2011 21:31:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/10/04/map-and-reduce-in-mapreduce-a-sas-illustration/</guid>
      <description>In last post, I mentioned Hadoop, the open source implementation of Google’s MapReduce for parallelized processing of big data. In this long National Holiday, I read the original Google paper, _MapReduce: Simplified Data Processing on Large Clusters_ by Jeffrey Dean and Sanjay Ghemawat and got that the terminologies of “map” and “reduce” were basically borrowed from Lisp, an old functional language that I even didn’t play “hello world” with. For Python users, the idea of Map and Reduce is also very straightforward because the workhorse data structure in Python is just the list, a sequence of values that you can just imagine that they are the nodes(clusters, chunk servers, …) in a distributed system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Selection: Collections for Self Study</title>
      <link>/2011/01/15/feature-selection-collections-for-self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2011 10:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/15/feature-selection-collections-for-self-study/</guid>
      <description>Recently I start to learn the algorithms and applications of feature selection. The term “Feature”, wildly used in machine learning and data mining literatures, simply means “Variable”. In some practices, for example, a neural network model uses a decision tree as input; the tree performs the function of variables selection.
The Arizona State University is maintaining a repository of feature selection, including original documentations, Matlab packages and user guide for the following popular algorithms so far:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision Trees in SAS Enterprise Miner and SPSS Clementine</title>
      <link>/2011/01/04/decision-trees-in-sas-enterprise-miner-and-spss-clementine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 20:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/04/decision-trees-in-sas-enterprise-miner-and-spss-clementine/</guid>
      <description>Decision trees are included in SAS Enterprise Miner(EM). The counterpart is SPSS Clementine, which should be called IBM SPSS Modeler for precision after IBM’s acquisition of SPSS.
Recently I read a paper on the comparisons of SAS EM, SPSS Clementine and IBM Intelligent Miner on their decision tree and cluster technology:
 _Decision Tree Induction &amp;amp; Clustering Techniques in SAS Enterprise Miner, SPSS Clementine, and IBM Intelligent Miner – A Comparative Analysis_ by Abdullah M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run data mining codes following William Potts</title>
      <link>/2009/03/20/run-data-mining-codes-following-william-potts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/20/run-data-mining-codes-following-william-potts/</guid>
      <description>FYI: SAS Enterprise Miner and SAS Text Miner Procedures: Reference for SAS 9.1.3, see:   &amp;nbsp;   http://support.sas.com/documentation/onlinedoc/miner/emtmsas913/listing.html   &amp;nbsp;   This entry DOES exist in the SAS Support website, but it can&amp;#8217;t be found by any search engine or documentation tree view. You&amp;#8217;re recommended to download these files immediately due to SAS&amp;#8217;s easy-dead hyperlinks.^-^    &amp;nbsp;   ps.SAS Institute provides no support for the use of Enterprise Miner and Text Miner Procedures when they are invoked directly, outside of the Enterprise Miner graphical user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Machine Learning Courses (Stanford) in YouTube</title>
      <link>/2009/03/02/free-machine-learning-courses-stanford-in-youtube/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 10:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/02/free-machine-learning-courses-stanford-in-youtube/</guid>
      <description> FYI:   &amp;nbsp;   http://www.youtube.com/view_play_list?p=A89DCFA6ADACE599  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS User Books and Data Mining Software Comparision: Quick Links</title>
      <link>/2009/02/17/sas-user-books-and-data-mining-software-comparision-quick-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/17/sas-user-books-and-data-mining-software-comparision-quick-links/</guid>
      <description> SAS Books Catalog(Jan, 2009) Data Mining Software 2009: Succesul Analyses at Affordable Prices(Nov. 2008, by mayato)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Review: SAS and Teradata Partnership</title>
      <link>/2008/12/19/industry-review-sas-and-teradata-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/19/industry-review-sas-and-teradata-partnership/</guid>
      <description>SAS and Teradata Partnership: Press   Leading Companies See Value in SAS and Teradata Partnership SAS and Teradata Unveil Advantage Program to Bring Powerful In-Database Solutions and Services to Customers SAS and Teradata Enter into Strategic Partnership    In BI industry, the pure players such as SAS, Teradata and Microstrategy, need to demonstrate their indispensable values against the megavendors, IBM (acquired Cognos), SAP (acquired Business Object), Oracle (acquired Hyperion) and Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining in Stock Market</title>
      <link>/2008/12/13/data-mining-in-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/13/data-mining-in-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>Data Mining in Stock Market? Is it crazy? or is it just a hopeless try? Every mentor in mathematics and finance educates us that the stock market is too chaotic and sentimental to use mathematical models. Most of all gift rock scientists are concentrated in the study of interest of rates and fixed income securities. It sounds profitable to use mathematical and statistical models to predict the price of stock, but there are little successfull stories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>