<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notepad&#43;&#43; on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/notepad&#43;&#43;/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notepad&#43;&#43; on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 23:10:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/notepad++/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tab is a Tab is a Tab is a Tab</title>
      <link>/2012/07/14/tab-is-a-tab-is-a-tab-is-a-tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 23:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/14/tab-is-a-tab-is-a-tab-is-a-tab/</guid>
      <description>Well I’m a big fan of “tabs” and feel much more comfortable when launching everything into tabs: web pages, text files, PDF files, Windows Office files (Word, Excel, PPT), and even folders.&amp;#160; Followings are my best of choices to share:
1. File Explorer: Clover  http://ejie.me/
 


There are lots of fancy/complicated file/folder management system beyond Windows Explore (Total Commander might be the most famous one) while Clover, as its name indicates, is just as simple as I need:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sublime Text 2 for SAS Programmers: A Quick Note</title>
      <link>/2012/07/13/sublime-text-2-for-sas-programmers-a-quick-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jul 2012 00:27:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/13/sublime-text-2-for-sas-programmers-a-quick-note/</guid>
      <description>I’m playing with a new text editor, Sublime Text 2, and it has much potentials to replace my current handy Notepad++ and VIM. A quick note for further exploration(will keep update).
/**update: 2012-10-16, Roy Pardee maintains a nice bundle (here), so the following bundle will be not updated any more.*****/
Also created a Github repository to hold all my SAS configuration files for Sublime Text 2. Fork me at</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face Off: Review OpenCDISC XML files</title>
      <link>/2012/02/11/face-off-review-opencdisc-xml-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 16:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/02/11/face-off-review-opencdisc-xml-files/</guid>
      <description>OpenCDISC, the first open source CDISC validator, is already in the toolbox of FDA reviewers (CDER/CBER, see CDISC Standards in the Regulatory Submission Process, 26 January 2012, P.33). The key features in OpenCDISC is a dichotomy of validation rules (XML based) and application logic. Currently OpenCDISC Validator (Version 1.2.1) officially supports the four following CDISC modules:
 SDTM 3.1.2 SDTM 3.1.1 Define.xml 1.0 ADaM 1.0  
You can get the corresponding configuration files (validation rules) online or in the software folder (in .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>