<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Industry Review on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/categories/industry-review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Industry Review on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 23:09:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/industry-review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;rsquo;s New</title>
      <link>/2013/03/20/whatrsquos-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 23:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/03/20/whatrsquos-new/</guid>
      <description>I didn’t blog for a while in this first half March and there are bunches of new stuff to catch up:
I had a new baby! He was delivered on time (and on budget!), lions tigers and bears, oh my&amp;#8230; His brother is Tiger so I named him, Leo.
And I got the latest SAS 9.3 (TS1M2) installed! SAS is jus getting much beautiful.

OpenCDISC had the latest release, Version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github for Clinical/Statistical Programmers</title>
      <link>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</guid>
      <description>PhUSE-FDA Working Group 5 (Development of Standard Scripts for Analysis and Programming) just adopted Google Code as collaborative programming platform. Google Code is one of the most popular and respected open source software hosting sites in the world and it is definitely a good choice for PhUSE-FDA WG5.
But after viewing one of WG5’s working reports, Sharing Standard Statistical Scripts and getting to know why they finally chose Google Code (rather than Github which was also tested by WG5 members), I think it’s necessary to clarify some misunderstanding against Github where I’m also an occasional user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great, Open, Vendor-neutral, Platform-independent Data Standards, . . . Yet in PDF Formats</title>
      <link>/2012/12/29/the-great-open-vendor-neutral-platform-independent-data-standards-.-.-.-yet-in-pdf-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 17:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/29/the-great-open-vendor-neutral-platform-independent-data-standards-.-.-.-yet-in-pdf-formats/</guid>
      <description>You know I mean the CDISC standards including CDASH, SDTM, SEND, ADaM, … and you are right there are few not only in PDF format (ODM, define.xml for example).
Today Jozef (Jos) Aerts from XML4Pharma posted his frustration of copying and pasting metadata from only PDF-formed SDTM-IG 3.1.4.&amp;#160; I hate to complain the volunteer work by the CDISC team but it is worth a discussion, is there any better way to publish CDISC Standards?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Clips: Data Scientist Episode II</title>
      <link>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 15:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</guid>
      <description>1. What is A Data Scientist Anyway?

2. You Just Can’t Be Replaced by Yourselves!

3. We are all Data Scientists!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Clip: Data Scientist</title>
      <link>/2012/11/30/weekend-clip-data-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 22:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/30/weekend-clip-data-scientist/</guid>
      <description>Two tweets: 

One blog post: _Statisticians aren’t the problem for data science. The real problem is too many posers_
One job advertisement: SAS Data Scientist ?(!)
A joke: The biggest joke about data scientist is that the Google query “data scientist joke” returns nothing interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There Any Better Way? Publishing Process For CDISC Standards Documentation</title>
      <link>/2012/07/19/is-there-any-better-way-publishing-process-for-cdisc-standards-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 01:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/19/is-there-any-better-way-publishing-process-for-cdisc-standards-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#160; 1. The Pain I read from Lex Jansen (@LexJansen) that CDISC SDTM v1.3 and SDTMIG v3.1.3 were newly released. It’s pretty nice since CDISC SDTM was supposed to be released semiannually in the new publishing cycle. We can see the team put great efforts on this new version, but frankly speaking, this delivery (the way to display, not the content itself) is far away elegant.
The new SDTM Implementation Guide (IG) v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging is Awesome: CDISC Bloggers</title>
      <link>/2012/05/04/blogging-is-awesome-cdisc-bloggers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 22:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/05/04/blogging-is-awesome-cdisc-bloggers/</guid>
      <description>I remember when blogging was cool.
Before the specializing and monetizing and Twitter-izing.
&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;#8212;Peter Dewolf
 Well I think blogging is still cool (and awesome_ and _awesome …). The most appealing personal reason is, blog posts are Google searchable and suitable for archive while Tweets NOT. Admittedly I hold some sort of&amp;#160; Existentialism 2.0: 
 if it is not Google searched, it doesn’t exit!
 Last month I placed a post on how to keep pace with CDISC&amp;#160;from its official channels and I feel cool to add an appendix of source from the awesome blogosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analytical Valley: Big Data and Data Scientists (and SAS Programmers)</title>
      <link>/2011/09/14/an-analytical-valley-big-data-and-data-scientists-and-sas-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 22:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/14/an-analytical-valley-big-data-and-data-scientists-and-sas-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Tom Davenport reported an observation that Silicon Valley is becoming more analytical since companies in the Valley such as Google, Facebook, eBay, LinkedLn all have strong presences in analytics. Besides such predominant companies, I’d also like to add Yahoo to the list although Yahoo is no longer in its peak. Yahoo is the largest sponsor and contributor of Hadoop, an open source framework for distributed processing of so called “big data”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision Trees in SAS Enterprise Miner and SPSS Clementine</title>
      <link>/2011/01/04/decision-trees-in-sas-enterprise-miner-and-spss-clementine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 20:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/04/decision-trees-in-sas-enterprise-miner-and-spss-clementine/</guid>
      <description>Decision trees are included in SAS Enterprise Miner(EM). The counterpart is SPSS Clementine, which should be called IBM SPSS Modeler for precision after IBM’s acquisition of SPSS.
Recently I read a paper on the comparisons of SAS EM, SPSS Clementine and IBM Intelligent Miner on their decision tree and cluster technology:
 _Decision Tree Induction &amp;amp; Clustering Techniques in SAS Enterprise Miner, SPSS Clementine, and IBM Intelligent Miner – A Comparative Analysis_ by Abdullah M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R or SAS: Quick Links to the Recent Debates</title>
      <link>/2009/01/13/r-or-sas-quick-links-to-the-recent-debates/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 10:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/13/r-or-sas-quick-links-to-the-recent-debates/</guid>
      <description>Original post, 7 Jan, 2009       New York Times, Data Analysts Captivated by R&amp;#8217;s Power byAshlee Vance.     
Key Point     The popularity of R at universities could threaten SAS Institute.     
A Controversial Review by Anee Milley from SAS       We have customers who build engines for aircraft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links: Risk Intelligence Vendors Review: 2008</title>
      <link>/2008/12/25/links-risk-intelligence-vendors-review-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2008 16:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/25/links-risk-intelligence-vendors-review-2008/</guid>
      <description>You can get the big picture viewing different sources(REMEMBER: A vendor&amp;#8217;s research methodology is as important as its rating):
  &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Chartis RiskTech 100 (October 2008)&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.chartisresearch.com/showreport.asp?id=46&amp;quot;&amp;gt;http://www.chartisresearch.com/showreport.asp?id=46&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_qlX7zyUQhog/SVNELKlQf2I/AAAAAAAABBk/O9jIagazNHU/s1600-h/RiskTech100-2008.PNG&amp;quot; onblur=&amp;quot;try {parent.deselectBloggerImageGracefully();} catch(e) {}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;img id=&amp;quot;BLOGGER_PHOTO_ID_5283641746445598562&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;cursor: pointer; width: 320px; height: 290px;&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_qlX7zyUQhog/SVNELKlQf2I/AAAAAAAABBk/O9jIagazNHU/s320/RiskTech100-2008.PNG&amp;quot; border=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 85%;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;img src=&amp;quot;cid:01d201c9666a$7afda6e0$22121bac@apac.sas.com&amp;quot; border=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; alt=&amp;quot;&amp;quot; hspace=&amp;quot;0&amp;quot; align=&amp;quot;baseline&amp;quot; /&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt; FinTech100(2008)&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links&amp;#8211;BI Industry 2008: Review and Prospect</title>
      <link>/2008/12/24/links#8211bi-industry-2008-review-and-prospect/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Dec 2008 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/24/links#8211bi-industry-2008-review-and-prospect/</guid>
      <description> /*Thanks the hints supplied by: 
   A look back at 2008 and some crystal ball predictions&amp;#8230;, byTammi Kay Geroge, from SASBlog*/     Major Data Warehousing Events of 2008 (and Predictions for 2009), by Michael Schiff, from TDWI,      Major Data Warehousing Events of 2008:      Everyone had an appliance story   Industry consolidations continued   The recessionary environment encourage further BI developments   Open source grew         Predictions for 2009:      Further industry consolidation(Informatica by HP, SPSS by SAP)   Cloud computing will come down to earth   Open source growth will accelerate   The IT world will become greener   Major emphasis on solutions rather than tools and technology        BusinessIntelligence Tools: Year in Review，by Cindi Howson, fromBeyeNetwork    Top Virtualization Trends for 2009, by John Suit, from ZDNet    Surround the Warehouse: Prediction for 2009 , by Neil Raden, from IntelligentEnterprise    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Review: SAS and Teradata Partnership</title>
      <link>/2008/12/19/industry-review-sas-and-teradata-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/19/industry-review-sas-and-teradata-partnership/</guid>
      <description>SAS and Teradata Partnership: Press   Leading Companies See Value in SAS and Teradata Partnership SAS and Teradata Unveil Advantage Program to Bring Powerful In-Database Solutions and Services to Customers SAS and Teradata Enter into Strategic Partnership    In BI industry, the pure players such as SAS, Teradata and Microstrategy, need to demonstrate their indispensable values against the megavendors, IBM (acquired Cognos), SAP (acquired Business Object), Oracle (acquired Hyperion) and Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Making of an Analyst: A Supplement to What Makes a Good Business Analyst</title>
      <link>/2008/12/17/the-making-of-an-analyst-a-supplement-to-what-makes-a-good-business-analyst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2008 09:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/17/the-making-of-an-analyst-a-supplement-to-what-makes-a-good-business-analyst/</guid>
      <description>I once commented the entry, What Makes a Good Business Analyst by Rajan Chandras, with an easy tone, If You Can Make it Here, You Can Make it Anywhere. The standards of a good analyst conclude by Rajan, in my opinion, are somewhat of very high bars.
  &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;In the recent SASCOM Magazine, Ted Cuzzillo published a relatively moderate enty, say, &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;&amp;lt;a href=&amp;quot;http://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>If You Can Make it Here, You Can Make it Anywhere: On What Makes a Good Business Analyst by Rajan Chandras</title>
      <link>/2008/12/14/if-you-can-make-it-here-you-can-make-it-anywhere-on-what-makes-a-good-business-analyst-by-rajan-chandras/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2008 00:24:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/14/if-you-can-make-it-here-you-can-make-it-anywhere-on-what-makes-a-good-business-analyst-by-rajan-chandras/</guid>
      <description>In the latest post, What Makes a Good Business Analyst?, Rajan Chandras cites some soft items from Forrester&amp;#8217;s Business Analyst Assessment Workbook:
 
 Ability to think abstractly, identify patterns, and generate ideas and solutions Understanding of when and how to escalate issues or needs Understanding of and ability to delivery the appropriate level of detail needed for each task Interest in exploring and understanding new concepts and topic areas Emotionally invested in the work Ability to learn by shadowing stakeholders Ability to clearly articulate technology in terms stakeholders can understand Understanding of the organizational culture and its impact on processes and projects (this one seems obvious, but the latter phrase is more profound than might seem at first glance) Ability to drive a decision analysis and selection process Ability to recognize patterns in requirements and categorize them appropriately  What&amp;#8217;s more, there are some suggestions by Rajan Chandras himself:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>