<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>misc on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/categories/misc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in misc on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:01:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/misc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Github for Clinical/Statistical Programmers</title>
      <link>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</guid>
      <description>PhUSE-FDA Working Group 5 (Development of Standard Scripts for Analysis and Programming) just adopted Google Code as collaborative programming platform. Google Code is one of the most popular and respected open source software hosting sites in the world and it is definitely a good choice for PhUSE-FDA WG5.
But after viewing one of WG5’s working reports, Sharing Standard Statistical Scripts and getting to know why they finally chose Google Code (rather than Github which was also tested by WG5 members), I think it’s necessary to clarify some misunderstanding against Github where I’m also an occasional user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Statistics: 2012</title>
      <link>/2013/01/01/blog-statistics-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 23:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/01/blog-statistics-2012/</guid>
      <description>(This blog’s page view data from Google Analytics; 43 posts in total in 2012)
Top 10 countries/territories and cities 
 Most of my readers come from US and I’m glad my Chinese fellows still fork me since I moved to US this year (today is my one year anniversary in US). To my surprising there are much more readers from South Korea than from Japan(#12) and Singapore(#22). Readers from a secret city (#7) are watching me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Clips: Data Scientist Episode II</title>
      <link>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 15:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</guid>
      <description>1. What is A Data Scientist Anyway?

2. You Just Can’t Be Replaced by Yourselves!

3. We are all Data Scientists!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is There Any Better Way? Publishing Process For CDISC Standards Documentation</title>
      <link>/2012/07/19/is-there-any-better-way-publishing-process-for-cdisc-standards-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jul 2012 01:54:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/19/is-there-any-better-way-publishing-process-for-cdisc-standards-documentation/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#160; 1. The Pain I read from Lex Jansen (@LexJansen) that CDISC SDTM v1.3 and SDTMIG v3.1.3 were newly released. It’s pretty nice since CDISC SDTM was supposed to be released semiannually in the new publishing cycle. We can see the team put great efforts on this new version, but frankly speaking, this delivery (the way to display, not the content itself) is far away elegant.
The new SDTM Implementation Guide (IG) v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tab is a Tab is a Tab is a Tab</title>
      <link>/2012/07/14/tab-is-a-tab-is-a-tab-is-a-tab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 23:10:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/07/14/tab-is-a-tab-is-a-tab-is-a-tab/</guid>
      <description>Well I’m a big fan of “tabs” and feel much more comfortable when launching everything into tabs: web pages, text files, PDF files, Windows Office files (Word, Excel, PPT), and even folders.&amp;#160; Followings are my best of choices to share:
1. File Explorer: Clover  http://ejie.me/
 


There are lots of fancy/complicated file/folder management system beyond Windows Explore (Total Commander might be the most famous one) while Clover, as its name indicates, is just as simple as I need:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Post Beats Menu Cost</title>
      <link>/2012/03/24/us-post-beats-menu-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 01:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/24/us-post-beats-menu-cost/</guid>
      <description>One of the interesting observations in my first few months in US: there is no price printed in the new mail stamps!
It is interesting because as a former student of economics, I think US Post system did a nice attempt to beat the so called “menu cost” which should honor to Harvard economist Mankiw. Literally the menu cost is the cost of a restaurant to print new menus due to price adjustment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year (Yes Again)</title>
      <link>/2012/01/24/happy-new-year-yes-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jan 2012 12:06:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/01/24/happy-new-year-yes-again/</guid>
      <description>Then I feel great to reset my year of 2012 as brand new one.
Today, Jan 23, is the first day of Chinese New Year, and it is Monday, the first day of work week&amp;#8211;it is always joyful to have such coincidenceJ. HAPPY NEW YEAR!
I had a big move this year. Actually I passed through multiply new years of 2012: I took my flight from Beijing in Jan 1 (happy new year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Python</title>
      <link>/2011/10/31/hello-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2011 20:29:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/10/31/hello-python/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Jian’s polyglot programming practice, I also begin to brush up Python and C++ which I learned during graduate school. Following is a Python response to one of Jian Dai’s former programming challenges for lines count of source codes:
[cce lang=&amp;#8221;python&amp;#8221;]
import os
#count number of lines of
#single file
def lineCount(fileName):
countSingle=0
for line in open(fileName):
countSingle += 1
return countSingle
#count number of lines of
#directory and subdirectories</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fours Errors in SAS 9.2 Fisher&amp;#8217;s Iris Data in SASHELP Library</title>
      <link>/2011/09/03/fours-errors-in-sas-9.2-fisher#8217s-iris-data-in-sashelp-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2011 21:13:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/03/fours-errors-in-sas-9.2-fisher#8217s-iris-data-in-sashelp-library/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/iris.gif&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-bottom: 0px; border-left: 0px; display: block; float: none; margin-left: auto; border-top: 0px; margin-right: auto; border-right: 0px&#34; title=&#34;iris&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;iris&#34; src=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/iris_thumb.gif&#34; width=&#34;240&#34; height=&#34;237&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/2011/08/31/who-is-alfred/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, I just mentioned that &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iris_flower_data_set&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fisher&amp;#8217;s Iris Data&lt;/a&gt; is embedded officially in SASHELP library in SAS 9.2. Note that even in SAS 9.1.3, you can also find this data with several instances from some demos in user guide (just search &amp;ldquo;Iris&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;SAS Help and Documentation&amp;rdquo; accompany with you SAS product), for example, in &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.sas.com/onlinedoc/913/getDoc/en/imlug.hlp/graphstart_sect13.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SAS 9.1.3 IML&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iris dataset is so important and popular that researchers round the world use it as benchmark to test and compare their algorithms and also as pedagogical purpose. It is also the overwhelming No. 1 dataset considering popularity in &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;UCI Machine Learning Repository&lt;/a&gt;. Here 4 errors in SASHELP.iris listed for your consideration if interested and if you find some slightly differences in outputs following some demos out of SAS using this data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error 1: Line 35, the PetalWidth of Setosa should be 2 mm, not 1 mm;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Error 2: Line 38, the SepalWidth of Setosa should be 36 mm, not 31 mm;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Error 3: Line 38, the PetalLength of Setosa should be 14 mm, not 15 mm;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Error 4: Line 119, the PetalLength of Virginica should be 69 mm, not 70 mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For errors 1-3, there is also an interesting story in statistical literature. In 1936, Fisher the Great published his famous paper, _&lt;a href=&#34;http://rcs.chph.ras.ru/Tutorials/classification/Fisher.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The use of multiple measurements in taxonomic problems&lt;/a&gt;_ and the Iris data also attached (called &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;Fisher Version&lt;/font&gt; in this post). In the following years (until today), people &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/datasets/Iris&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;cited&lt;/a&gt; this paper and the Iris data Fisher Version is also replicated and distributed worldwide and then a version with above errors 1-3 might gain a very dominant popularity (I don’t know the source of there errors). In UCI Machine Learning Repository, the dataset &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/iris/iris.data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;iris.data&lt;/a&gt; is the one with such 3 errors (called &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;UCI Version&lt;/font&gt; as well).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We could see that the duplicated UCI Version is even more popular in some extension than its original Fisher Version (SASHELP.iris also seems to be copied from UCI Version). Story goes on. In 1998, James Bezdek and other scholars just found the three discrepancies between Iris Fisher Version and UCI Version (and in some published papers using the same version of data). You can read it in _&lt;a href=&#34;http://pages.bangor.ac.uk/~mas00a/papers/jbjkrklknptfs99.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Will the Real Iris Data Please Stand Up?&lt;/a&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bezdek then proposed to use the original Fisher Version of Iris, and UCI Machine Learning Repository also &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/iris/iris.names&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;documented these three errors&lt;/a&gt; and added new dataset called &lt;a href=&#34;http://archive.ics.uci.edu/ml/machine-learning-databases/iris/bezdekIris.data&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;bezdekIris.data&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;Bezdek Version&lt;/font&gt;) which is exactly Fisher Version (iris.data kept and I think it is because now the so called error version is also valuable).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Return to error 4 and I can’t figure out why and I might as well call it Iris &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;SAS Version&lt;/font&gt;. Note that the unit in SAS Version is millimeter (mm), while others version all use centimeter (cm).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The interesting part is that I also check the &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.sas.com/onlinedoc/913/getDoc/en/imlug.hlp/graphstart_sect13.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Iris data in SAS 9.1.3 IML&lt;/a&gt; mentioned before and not surprising, it is exactly the Fisher Version (you can also find a right one in a demo from &lt;a href=&#34;http://support.sas.com/documentation/cdl/en/imlsug/62558/HTML/default/viewer.htm#ugappdatasets_sect11.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SAS 9.2 IML Studio 3.2&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following codes generate several Iris versions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;iris_uci: &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;UCI Version&lt;/font&gt; with both CM and MM as unit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bezdekiris_uci: &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;Bezdek Version&lt;/font&gt; or &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;Fisher Version&lt;/font&gt; with both CM and MM as unit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iris_mm: &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;UCI Version&lt;/font&gt; with MM as unit and attributes alike SASHELP.iris, &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;SAS Version&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bezdekiris_mm: &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;Bezdek Version&lt;/font&gt; or &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;Fisher Version&lt;/font&gt; with MM as unit and attributes alike SASHELP.iris, &lt;font color=&#34;#ff0000&#34;&gt;SAS Version&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is Alfred?</title>
      <link>/2011/08/31/who-is-alfred/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2011 22:18:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/31/who-is-alfred/</guid>
      <description>Tell me something about Alfred, male or female? age? height and weight?
 Oracle database (version 9 and below) had a well known default demo account SCOTT with a password, TIGER (and TIGER was the name of the real person Bruce Scott ’s cat, see) and in this account, there are some tables named DEPT, EMP, BONUS and SALGRADE (you can read their meaning). Almost every Oracle DBA learn SQL using these database and an joke just says that in DBA’s meetings, people just&amp;#160; warm up saying “how about Smith?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am a 20% SAS Nerd!</title>
      <link>/2011/08/23/i-am-a-20-sas-nerd/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2011 21:57:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/08/23/i-am-a-20-sas-nerd/</guid>
      <description>Kirk Paul Lafler drafted a checking list for identifying a SAS nerd (or geek, in its positive ways) in one of his intriguing papers:
 _You Could be a SAS® Nerd If &amp;hellip;_
 Here I’m glad to find that I am roughly a 20% SAS nerd (12 matched in all 57 lists):
  You blog SAS-related comments and technical solutions frequently.
 You have more than five SAS blogs in your RSS feed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS Bloggers In Action(1): Rick Wicklin, SAS/IML and &amp;ldquo;Color Revolution&amp;rdquo;</title>
      <link>/2011/07/17/sas-bloggers-in-action1-rick-wicklin-sas/iml-and-ldquocolor-revolutionrdquo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 16:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/17/sas-bloggers-in-action1-rick-wicklin-sas/iml-and-ldquocolor-revolutionrdquo/</guid>
      <description>It is well known that the French writer, author of The Three Musketeer, Alexandre Dumas, wrote his master piece of work in different colored papers according to literary genre:
 non-fiction on&amp;#160; rose,
fiction on blue,
poetry on yellow
 The SAS blog writer, author of Statistical Programming with SAS/IML Software, Rick Wicklin of SAS Institute,&amp;#160; also leads a strong “color revolution” in SAS blog community:
In an interesting personal statement, Blogging, Programming, and Johari Windows, Rick summarizes his rich and colorful blogging rhythms according to the above Johari window:&amp;#160;&amp;#160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tango Haiku</title>
      <link>/2011/07/15/tango-haiku/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2011 22:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/15/tango-haiku/</guid>
      <description>Happy weekend and Haiku again!
 My finger hurts,
I can not dance
Tango in Bastille.
 So… any ideas?
…
… …
… … …
OK. I am a terrible Haiku writer. The sentences are not self explained without&amp;#160; /*commentaries*/ . So the story behind the scene…
One day my remote workstation was very very slow due to some network issues. But I still needed to write and run SAS codes in the server which is located in France.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ADJECTIVE Encounters</title>
      <link>/2011/07/02/adjective-encounters/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2011 10:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/02/adjective-encounters/</guid>
      <description>Really she is the strangest creature in the world, far from heroic, variable as a weathercock, “bashful, insolent; chaste, lustful; prating, silent; laborious, delicate; ingenious, heavy; melancholic, pleasant; lying, true; knowing, ignorant; liberal, covetous, and prodigal”— in short, so complex, so indefinite, …
&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;#8211;Virginia Woolf, The Common Reader, First Series (1925)
 I don’t know if Ernest Hemingway is still one of the recognized dominant writers in colleges English education.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too Big to Be Accurate(1): Which is the Most Powerful Calculator in the World?</title>
      <link>/2011/01/22/too-big-to-be-accurate1-which-is-the-most-powerful-calculator-in-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2011 17:05:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/22/too-big-to-be-accurate1-which-is-the-most-powerful-calculator-in-the-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Calculate the factorial of 171 (171!)? Just TRY! It is equal to 171*170*169*….2*1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-google-calculator&#34;&gt;1. Google calculator&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As Google fanatics, I first try to search the answer via Google:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Google171.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-right-width: 0px; display: block; float: none; border-top-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; margin-left: auto; border-left-width: 0px; margin-right: auto&#34; title=&#34;Google171&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Google171&#34; src=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Google171_thumb.png&#34; width=&#34;336&#34; height=&#34;116&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoops, nothing interested returned! Type “170!” and get the output:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Google170.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-right-width: 0px; display: block; float: none; border-top-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; margin-left: auto; border-left-width: 0px; margin-right: auto&#34; title=&#34;Google170&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Google170&#34; src=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Google170_thumb.png&#34; width=&#34;244&#34; height=&#34;110&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Why kinda things happened in this calculator? 171! is just equal to 171*170!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-excel&#34;&gt;2. Excel&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Switch to Excel spreadsheet. Function fact(*) used:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Excel170.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-right-width: 0px; display: block; float: none; border-top-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; margin-left: auto; border-left-width: 0px; margin-right: auto&#34; title=&#34;Excel170&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Excel170&#34; src=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Excel170_thumb.png&#34; width=&#34;228&#34; height=&#34;66&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Excel171.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img style=&#34;border-right-width: 0px; display: block; float: none; border-top-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; margin-left: auto; border-left-width: 0px; margin-right: auto&#34; title=&#34;Excel171&#34; border=&#34;0&#34; alt=&#34;Excel171&#34; src=&#34;http://www.jiangtanghu.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2011/01/Excel171_thumb.png&#34; width=&#34;244&#34; height=&#34;64&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Oo, interesting. The same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-sas&#34;&gt;3. SAS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google and Excel may be the niche players in calculators’ family. Why not try to use some programming languages?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SGF: Caesars Palace in Las Vegas again</title>
      <link>/2010/12/30/sgf-caesars-palace-in-las-vegas-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 18:13:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/12/30/sgf-caesars-palace-in-las-vegas-again/</guid>
      <description>The mechanic, who wishes to do his work well, must first  sharpen his tools. --Confucian Analects. BOOK XV.WEI LING KUNG.CHAP.IX.  My paper _Work Smarter than Harder-tools for growing up a SAS programmer_ was accepted by SAS Global Forum 2011. It would be my first time to attend SAS user group conference worldwide. The draft version is available at
http://jiangtanghu.com/docs/en/SGF2011_JiangtangHU(draft).pdf.pdf&amp;rdquo;)
Welcome for any comments.
The SGF2011 will be held at Caesars Palace in Las Vegas, Nevada.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A SAS Programmer&amp;rsquo;s End Year Haiku</title>
      <link>/2010/12/30/a-sas-programmerrsquos-end-year-haiku/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2010 16:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/12/30/a-sas-programmerrsquos-end-year-haiku/</guid>
      <description>End year Haiku again!
Yesterday I finished my project, wrote a Haiku to colleagues worldwide to say happy new year, then closed my desktop, said goodbye to colleagues still in office:
 In December my baby born
my project deliveries followed on
Now my computers shutdown
do until(6 Jan 2011) I will be OOO
Please take blessings from John
 Happy New Year!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blogging SAS</title>
      <link>/2010/11/30/blogging-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2010 21:16:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/11/30/blogging-sas/</guid>
      <description>Almost at the same time, there are two SAS blogs aggregators popping up to the web for SAS programmers worldwide, one in Chinese, the other, English:
 http://saslist.com/&amp;#160; in Chinese, maintained by sxlion, also the owner of a SAS information site,&amp;#160; http://saslist.net/
http://sas-x.com/&amp;#160;&amp;#160; in English, maintained by Tal Galili, also the owner of R blogs aggregator, http://r-bloggers.com/
 I try to express in a very symmetrical way. What’s more (and interesting), these two aggregators share a same WordPress template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursive Referencing and Binomial Proportion Interval</title>
      <link>/2010/11/03/recursive-referencing-and-binomial-proportion-interval/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 20:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/11/03/recursive-referencing-and-binomial-proportion-interval/</guid>
      <description>To understand recursion, one of the most important concepts in programming languages, you could watch the movie, Chris Nolan’s Inception: it is about a dream within a dream within a dream, …and, read two statistical papers by Professor Robert Newcombe, one of the most prolific statisticians:
 Two-sided confidence intervals for the single proportion: comparison of seven methods. 
Newcombe RG, Stat Med , Volume 17 , 8 (April 1998) pp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On three statistical realms</title>
      <link>/2010/10/06/on-three-statistical-realms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 11:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/10/06/on-three-statistical-realms/</guid>
      <description>Peter Petocz and Anna Reid(2010) grouped three levels of students’ conceptions of statistics:
 Level I:&amp;#160;&amp;#160; focus on techniques Level II:&amp;#160; focus on using data Level III: focus on meaning  I found the three conceptions could be easily interpreted as the three kinds of state of learning and using statistics based on my personal experience:
 State I: focus on techniques—As a student of Economics and (then) Software Engineering, I needed some statistics techniques to support my study on data mining and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From A Logical Point of View</title>
      <link>/2009/12/21/from-a-logical-point-of-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2009 23:53:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/12/21/from-a-logical-point-of-view/</guid>
      <description>This blog, “From A Logical Point of View”, is not supposed to be owned by a logician. Actually, the book, From A Logical Point of View, is a collection of logical and philosophical essays by W.V.Quine(1908-2000), an American philosopher and mathematician. 
A story about this book. From A Logical Point of View, was a calypso song by Robert Mitchum, an US actor, composer and singer. Quine enjoyed this music and used it as his new book, which is Quine’s best seller.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy New Year</title>
      <link>/2009/01/01/happy-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 23:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/01/happy-new-year/</guid>
      <description>新年快乐 ( Xin Nian Kuai Le),
 Guten Rutsch ins neue Jahr,
Bonne Année,
Nav varsh ki shubh kamnayey,
Felice Anno Nuovo,
Feliz Año Nuevo,
Feliz Ano Novo,
明けましておめでとうございます (Akemashite Omedetô),
Gelukkig Nieuwjaar,
Szczęśliwego Nowego Roku,
Καλή Χρονιά (Kalí Chroniá),
Seh Heh Bok Mani Bat Uh Seyo,
חג חנוכה שמח (Hag Hanukkah Sameah),
Cчастливого Нового Года,  &amp;lt;p&amp;gt; Happy New Year, &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Haiku from SAS R&amp;amp;D staff</title>
      <link>/2008/12/10/haiku-from-sas-rampd-staff/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 11:37:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/10/haiku-from-sas-rampd-staff/</guid>
      <description>First prompts are silent.
Subsequent prompts loud and clear.
Now all prompts are heard.
 Poem from R&amp;amp;D staff?
Yes. Rhyming sonnets were shakespeare-like complex;
they wrote Japanese haiku, showed as above.
The SAS R&amp;amp;D staff should complete some paper work in defects system before changing a code. They use informal descriptive language(HAIKUUU!) in the early stage. Chris Hemedinger, a senior software engineer at SAS, collected some haikus in his blog to show the humor side of SAS R&amp;amp;D staff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy grow up</title>
      <link>/2008/12/10/happy-grow-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 10:21:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/10/happy-grow-up/</guid>
      <description>Happy hearts and happy faces,
Happy play in grassy places&amp;#8211;
&amp;#8211;Good and Bad Children by Robert Louis Stevenson   I read this verse in W. Bennentt&amp;#8217;s popular book, The Book of Virtues, during the bus-to-company time this morning. It&amp;#8217;s interesting to read Stevenson&amp;#8217;s Treasure Island, of course in Chinese edition when I was young.   &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial; font-size: 85%;&amp;quot;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt; &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div&amp;gt; &amp;lt;span style=&amp;quot;font-family: Arial;&amp;quot;&amp;gt;Yes, it sounds &amp;amp;#8220;uncool&amp;amp;#8221;, &amp;amp;#8211;I went to work, with technical documents in my bag, and read a for-children book.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>