<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Lost Time: 2016</title>
      <link>/2017/05/04/in-search-of-lost-time-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/04/in-search-of-lost-time-2016/</guid>
      <description>2016 was gone, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even leave one single blog post. An obvious inference should be, 2016 doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist&amp;hellip;
2016 was a year of struggle for me as a SAS programmer. I earn my bread mostly using SAS, but is a SAS programmer like me cool? It&amp;rsquo;s not a silly question. Lots of SAS programmers feel the crunch.
So, in 2016, I
 learned some Python, attended Pydata Carolinas, learned some Spark, and got certified by edX somehow with all the bubble words in the title, Distributed Machine Learning with Apache Spark, learned some math, Linear Algebra, learned more math, Probability, learned even more math, Numerical Analysis, and didn&amp;rsquo;t update one single blog post, because all my spare time and coffee making time were simply run out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Import .Rdata to SAS, along with Labels</title>
      <link>/2015/05/12/import-.rdata-to-sas-along-with-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 13:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/12/import-.rdata-to-sas-along-with-labels/</guid>
      <description>I didn’t play with SAS/IML for a while. I call it back when I need to read some R format data.
Technically, .Rdata is not a data format. It’s rather a big container to hold bunch of R objects:

In this example, when a .Rdata is loaded, 3 objects are included where ‘data’(the ‘real’ data) and ‘desc’ (data description portion) are of our interests.
SAS/IML offers a nice interface to call R command which can be used to read the R format data:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use List Object in SAS: Yet Another Undocumented Feature in SAS 9.4</title>
      <link>/2014/04/01/use-list-object-in-sas-yet-another-undocumented-feature-in-sas-9.4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 23:42:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/04/01/use-list-object-in-sas-yet-another-undocumented-feature-in-sas-9.4/</guid>
      <description>Last year I gave a talk in SESUG 2013 on list manipulation on SAS using a collection of function-like macros. Today I just explored in my recently upgraded SAS 9.4 that I can play with list natively, which means I can create a list, slice a list and do other list operations in Data Steps! This is not documented yet(which means it will not be supported by the software vendor) and I can see warning message in Log window like “WARNING: List object is preproduction in this release”, and it is still limited somehow, so use it in your own risk (and of course, fun).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hardware and Software 2013 I&amp;rsquo;m Most Thankful For</title>
      <link>/2013/11/29/the-hardware-and-software-2013-irsquom-most-thankful-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2013 00:16:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/11/29/the-hardware-and-software-2013-irsquom-most-thankful-for/</guid>
      <description>It’s time of year to give thanks. As a programmer, e-book reader, blog writer and web surfer, I should express my sincere appreciation to such hardware and software (I use majority of them at daily basis and most of them are free):
0. Hardware  Lenovo Thinkpad W520&amp;#160;(This is not free): my workhorse machine, now replaced by W530.
1. Google Stuff Google Chrome (Windows and Android apps): The first thing to do when getting a new machine is using IE to download the Chrome, then I can just keep moving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&amp;rsquo;s New</title>
      <link>/2013/03/20/whatrsquos-new/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2013 23:09:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/03/20/whatrsquos-new/</guid>
      <description>I didn’t blog for a while in this first half March and there are bunches of new stuff to catch up:
I had a new baby! He was delivered on time (and on budget!), lions tigers and bears, oh my&amp;#8230; His brother is Tiger so I named him, Leo.
And I got the latest SAS 9.3 (TS1M2) installed! SAS is jus getting much beautiful.

OpenCDISC had the latest release, Version 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github for Clinical/Statistical Programmers</title>
      <link>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</guid>
      <description>PhUSE-FDA Working Group 5 (Development of Standard Scripts for Analysis and Programming) just adopted Google Code as collaborative programming platform. Google Code is one of the most popular and respected open source software hosting sites in the world and it is definitely a good choice for PhUSE-FDA WG5.
But after viewing one of WG5’s working reports, Sharing Standard Statistical Scripts and getting to know why they finally chose Google Code (rather than Github which was also tested by WG5 members), I think it’s necessary to clarify some misunderstanding against Github where I’m also an occasional user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LearningR!</title>
      <link>/2013/02/08/learningr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 23:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/08/learningr/</guid>
      <description>I spent almost all of my blogging time last month to follow an online course in Coursera, Computing for Data Analysis (with R) by Dr. Roger&amp;#160; Peng of Johns Hopkins, Biostatistics Department. I already checked out bunch of Coursera courses just to take a look at what else MOOC look like, this R course was the first and only one I took seriously: I reviewed all slides (although didn’t watch the videos since I didn’t have enough time) and most important, finished all programming assignments(and got full score!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Clips: Data Scientist Episode II</title>
      <link>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 15:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</guid>
      <description>1. What is A Data Scientist Anyway?

2. You Just Can’t Be Replaced by Yourselves!

3. We are all Data Scientists!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporate SAS/IML to Base SAS?</title>
      <link>/2012/10/16/incorporate-sas/iml-to-base-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 22:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/16/incorporate-sas/iml-to-base-sas/</guid>
      <description>Since SAS 9.3, ODS Graphics was moved into Base SAS and other statistical procedures, which means the SAS/Graph license is not needed anymore to access ODS Graphics facilities. It’s definitely nice, but from customers’ point of view, it is not critical necessary: since the “minimum set of SAS system” in most SAS sessions includes the Base SAS, SAS/Stat and SAS/Graph, there is almost no impact for SAS users to switch the license of ODS Graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Set Up R (for SAS Programmers)</title>
      <link>/2012/09/30/set-up-r-for-sas-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2012 21:19:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/30/set-up-r-for-sas-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Yep, I am a SAS programmer: during the day time, I use SAS for my work; at the evening, I use R for entertainment.— Charlie Huang  Getting start to play with R (it is really a wonderful learning tool):
12. SAS IML Studio and R Integration (not tested) 11. SAS IML and R Integration (not tested) 10. SAS Base and R Integration: PROC R also a blog post.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is SAS Output Anyway?</title>
      <link>/2012/09/22/where-is-sas-output-anyway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 22:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/22/where-is-sas-output-anyway/</guid>
      <description>It is said in An Introduction to R, one of R official documents (Current Version: 2.15.1):
 There is an important difference in philosophy between S (and hence R) and the other main statistical systems. In S a statistical analysis is normally done as a series of steps, with intermediate results being stored in objects. Thus whereas SAS and SPSS will give copious output from a regression or discriminant analysis, R will give minimal output and store the results in a fit object for subsequent interrogation by further R functions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>