<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SAS XML Mapper on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/sas-xml-mapper/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SAS XML Mapper on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 01:13:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/sas-xml-mapper/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of SAS: A Personal Nomination 2012</title>
      <link>/2012/12/31/best-of-sas-a-personal-nomination-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 01:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/31/best-of-sas-a-personal-nomination-2012/</guid>
      <description>There SAS applications/procedures/features were not necessarily available since 2012. This year I paid special attention to them when began to use SAS 9.3. The following notes are&amp;#160; totally my personal endorsement purely based my own experience as a user:
XML File Reading: SAS XML Mapper 
SAS XML Mapper itself is not an elegant tool from software design perspective (an example: I keep multiple versions because the latest version seems not carry out all the functionalities from old ones), but it is best XML file processing tool for SAS programmers like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face Off: Review OpenCDISC XML files</title>
      <link>/2012/02/11/face-off-review-opencdisc-xml-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Feb 2012 16:35:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/02/11/face-off-review-opencdisc-xml-files/</guid>
      <description>OpenCDISC, the first open source CDISC validator, is already in the toolbox of FDA reviewers (CDER/CBER, see CDISC Standards in the Regulatory Submission Process, 26 January 2012, P.33). The key features in OpenCDISC is a dichotomy of validation rules (XML based) and application logic. Currently OpenCDISC Validator (Version 1.2.1) officially supports the four following CDISC modules:
 SDTM 3.1.2 SDTM 3.1.1 Define.xml 1.0 ADaM 1.0  
You can get the corresponding configuration files (validation rules) online or in the software folder (in .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>