<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>statistics on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in statistics on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 22:05:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (3B): Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion Using SAS, Updated</title>
      <link>/2015/05/22/statistical-notes-3b-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2015 22:05:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/22/statistical-notes-3b-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas-updated/</guid>
      <description>This quick note serves as a supplementnote of my previous Statistical Notes (3): Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion Using SAS which I will extend as a SESUG 2015 paper. Basically I added a new Blaker method to my CI_Single_Proportion.sas file and found more CIs from SAS PROC FREQ.
First of all, call the script:
 filename CI url “https://raw.github.com/Jiangtang/Programming-SAS/master/CI_Single_Proportion.sas” ; %include CI;
%CI_Single_Proportion(r=81,n=263);
 and the output:

The #12 is the one newly added.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community Contributors to SAS/STAT</title>
      <link>/2013/09/18/community-contributors-to-sas/stat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2013 19:24:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/09/18/community-contributors-to-sas/stat/</guid>
      <description>I suppose it is tempting, if the only tool you have is a hammer, to treat everything as if it were a nail. &amp;#8211; Abraham Maslow, The Psychology of Science, 1966
 Yes it’s true: since I have a pretty rich collection of SAS list processing macros, I’d like my list container to hold everything itemized. Here is a nail I found in SAS/STAT online help.
There are strong community contributing to the development of SAS/STAT software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noninferiority Testing with SAS</title>
      <link>/2013/08/26/noninferiority-testing-with-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 22:59:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/26/noninferiority-testing-with-sas/</guid>
      <description>I planed to extend nonWinferiority testing to one of my statistical notes,&amp;#160; Equivalence Testing and TOST (Two One-Sided Test) since noninferiority test is simply half part of the equivalence test. Today I’m glad to find an even better explanation from
 SAS Usage Note 48616: Design and analysis of noninferiority studies
 You will love it if you are interested in this subject (bookmark this link since it looks like unfinished somehow).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidence Intervals for Difference Between Independent Binomial Proportions: A SAS 9.4/STAT 12.3 Update</title>
      <link>/2013/08/25/confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 23:32:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/25/confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</guid>
      <description>For the computing of confidence intervals for difference between two independent binomial proportions in SAS 9.4/STAT 12.3, it’s hard to figure out exactly how many methods are available because there is no “CL=ALL” trigger in RISKDIFF option (but you can get one in BIONOMIAL option to compute the confidence intervals for binomial proportion). As far as I hacked, I got 11 intervals (last year I tried SAS 9.3 and got 8; codes available below):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion: A SAS 9.4/STAT 12.3 Update</title>
      <link>/2013/08/22/confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2013 10:57:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/08/22/confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-a-sas-9.4/stat-12.3-update/</guid>
      <description>1. A new confidence limits method added, Wilson (Corrected) 2. The binomialc option is no longer documented, but still works        After getting the access to SAS 9.4 alone with SAS/STAT 12.3, I first took a look at my favorite SAS statistical procedure, PROF FREQ.&amp;#160; Last year I had a note on confidence intervals for binomial proportion based on SAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Github for Clinical/Statistical Programmers</title>
      <link>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2013 22:01:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/20/github-for-clinical/statistical-programmers/</guid>
      <description>PhUSE-FDA Working Group 5 (Development of Standard Scripts for Analysis and Programming) just adopted Google Code as collaborative programming platform. Google Code is one of the most popular and respected open source software hosting sites in the world and it is definitely a good choice for PhUSE-FDA WG5.
But after viewing one of WG5’s working reports, Sharing Standard Statistical Scripts and getting to know why they finally chose Google Code (rather than Github which was also tested by WG5 members), I think it’s necessary to clarify some misunderstanding against Github where I’m also an occasional user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LearningR!</title>
      <link>/2013/02/08/learningr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2013 23:37:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/08/learningr/</guid>
      <description>I spent almost all of my blogging time last month to follow an online course in Coursera, Computing for Data Analysis (with R) by Dr. Roger&amp;#160; Peng of Johns Hopkins, Biostatistics Department. I already checked out bunch of Coursera courses just to take a look at what else MOOC look like, this R course was the first and only one I took seriously: I reviewed all slides (although didn’t watch the videos since I didn’t have enough time) and most important, finished all programming assignments(and got full score!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Statistics: 2012</title>
      <link>/2013/01/01/blog-statistics-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 23:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/01/01/blog-statistics-2012/</guid>
      <description>(This blog’s page view data from Google Analytics; 43 posts in total in 2012)
Top 10 countries/territories and cities 
 Most of my readers come from US and I’m glad my Chinese fellows still fork me since I moved to US this year (today is my one year anniversary in US). To my surprising there are much more readers from South Korea than from Japan(#12) and Singapore(#22). Readers from a secret city (#7) are watching me!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Clips: Data Scientist Episode II</title>
      <link>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2012 15:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/23/weekend-clips-data-scientist-episode-ii/</guid>
      <description>1. What is A Data Scientist Anyway?

2. You Just Can’t Be Replaced by Yourselves!

3. We are all Data Scientists!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My SAS Books: Shopping List 2012</title>
      <link>/2012/12/07/my-sas-books-shopping-list-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 23:36:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/07/my-sas-books-shopping-list-2012/</guid>
      <description>Last year I threw away all my SAS books (to friends and colleagues in Beijing) before moving to US. You might agree that it’s not economically bound to transport such heavy books intercontinentally! Now I just start to build my SAS library one by one. 
I will most probably not buy more SAS books as Christmas gifts for myself, so it’s time to take a 2012 snapshot of shopping:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekend Clip: Data Scientist</title>
      <link>/2012/11/30/weekend-clip-data-scientist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 22:31:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/30/weekend-clip-data-scientist/</guid>
      <description>Two tweets: 

One blog post: _Statisticians aren’t the problem for data science. The real problem is too many posers_
One job advertisement: SAS Data Scientist ?(!)
A joke: The biggest joke about data scientist is that the Google query “data scientist joke” returns nothing interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incorporate SAS/IML to Base SAS?</title>
      <link>/2012/10/16/incorporate-sas/iml-to-base-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2012 22:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/16/incorporate-sas/iml-to-base-sas/</guid>
      <description>Since SAS 9.3, ODS Graphics was moved into Base SAS and other statistical procedures, which means the SAS/Graph license is not needed anymore to access ODS Graphics facilities. It’s definitely nice, but from customers’ point of view, it is not critical necessary: since the “minimum set of SAS system” in most SAS sessions includes the Base SAS, SAS/Stat and SAS/Graph, there is almost no impact for SAS users to switch the license of ODS Graphics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (5): Confidence Intervals for Difference Between Independent Binomial Proportions Using SAS</title>
      <link>/2012/09/23/statistical-notes-5-confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-using-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Sep 2012 21:23:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/23/statistical-notes-5-confidence-intervals-for-difference-between-independent-binomial-proportions-using-sas/</guid>
      <description>A guy notices a bunch of targets scattered over a barn wall, and in the center of each, in the &amp;ldquo;bulls-eye,&amp;rdquo; is a bullet hole. &amp;ldquo;Wow,&amp;rdquo; he says to the farmer, &amp;ldquo;that&amp;#8217;s pretty good shooting. How&amp;#8217;d you do it?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Oh,&amp;rdquo; says the farmer, &amp;ldquo;it was easy. I painted the targets after I shot the holes.&amp;rdquo; – An Old Joke
 Note on how to get the difference between independent binomial proportions using SAS PROC FREQ (tested in SAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where is SAS Output Anyway?</title>
      <link>/2012/09/22/where-is-sas-output-anyway/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 22:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/22/where-is-sas-output-anyway/</guid>
      <description>It is said in An Introduction to R, one of R official documents (Current Version: 2.15.1):
 There is an important difference in philosophy between S (and hence R) and the other main statistical systems. In S a statistical analysis is normally done as a series of steps, with intermediate results being stored in objects. Thus whereas SAS and SPSS will give copious output from a regression or discriminant analysis, R will give minimal output and store the results in a fit object for subsequent interrogation by further R functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Book on Confidence Intervals for Proportions by Prof. Newcombe</title>
      <link>/2012/09/21/new-book-on-confidence-intervals-for-proportions-by-prof.-newcombe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 21:18:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/21/new-book-on-confidence-intervals-for-proportions-by-prof.-newcombe/</guid>
      <description>Check it out: a new book on confidence intervals for proportions by Prof. Robert G. Newcombe&amp;#160; just recently available from CRC Press:

 Confidence Intervals for Proportions and Related Measures of Effect Size
 This book also supplies a set of Excel spreadsheets to calculating CIs, see
 http://www.crcpress.com/product/isbn/9781439812785
 Other users may be interested on a SAS or R implementation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequentist or Baysian in A Binomial Test</title>
      <link>/2012/09/21/frequentist-or-baysian-in-a-binomial-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Sep 2012 01:20:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/21/frequentist-or-baysian-in-a-binomial-test/</guid>
      <description>A latest updated post on Freakonomics, Beware the Weasel Word “Statistical” in Statistical Significance!,&amp;#160; seemed to attempt to challenge frequentist statistics by Bayesian. I have no research on Bayesian and won’t jump to the debates. I’d rather to use this case to apply the Dragon’s Teeth and Fleas logic of hypothesis testing (at least I think frequentist is pretty intuitive). 
A story goes with this post, that Bob won 20 times out of total 30 rounds with Alice in a children card game, “War”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (4): Dragon&amp;rsquo;s Teeth and Fleas: Hypothesis Testing in Plain English</title>
      <link>/2012/09/16/statistical-notes-4-dragonrsquos-teeth-and-fleas-hypothesis-testing-in-plain-english/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2012 14:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/16/statistical-notes-4-dragonrsquos-teeth-and-fleas-hypothesis-testing-in-plain-english/</guid>
      <description>Statisticians aren’t the problem for data science. The real problem is too many posers &amp;#8212; Cathy O’Neil
you actually do need to understand how to invert a matrix at some point in your life if you want to be a data scientist. &amp;#8212; Cathy O’Neil
 
I was asked in several different occasions to explain hypothesis testing to non-technical people in plain English. Now I think I got a pretty neat one while honors belong to three great Germans, Friedrich Engels, Karl Marx, and Heinrich Heine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (3): Confidence Intervals for Binomial Proportion Using SAS</title>
      <link>/2012/09/15/statistical-notes-3-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2012 00:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/15/statistical-notes-3-confidence-intervals-for-binomial-proportion-using-sas/</guid>
      <description>A guy notices a bunch of targets scattered over a barn wall, and in the center of each, in the &amp;#8220;bulls-eye,&amp;#8221; is a bullet hole. &amp;#8220;Wow,&amp;#8221; he says to the farmer, &amp;#8220;that&amp;#8217;s pretty good shooting. How&amp;#8217;d you do it?&amp;#8221; &amp;#8220;Oh,&amp;#8221; says the farmer, &amp;#8220;it was easy. I painted the targets after I shot the holes.&amp;#8221; – An Old Joke
 Last year I dumped piece of SAS codes to compute confidence intervals for single proportion using 11 methods including 7 presented by one of Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (2): Equivalence Testing and TOST (Two One-Sided Test)</title>
      <link>/2012/09/12/statistical-notes-2-equivalence-testing-and-tost-two-one-sided-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 22:39:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/12/statistical-notes-2-equivalence-testing-and-tost-two-one-sided-test/</guid>
      <description>_Programmers Need to Learn Statistics Or I will Kill Them All –Zed A. Shaw_
 In an equivalence testing&amp;#160;example against lognormal data,&amp;#160; a TOST (Two One-Sided Test)&amp;#160; option used in SAS TTEST procedure:
 proc ttest data=auc dist=lognormal tost(0.8, 1.25); &amp;#160;&amp;#160; paired TestAUC*RefAUC; run;
 And the output:

Since the 90% (who not 95%? see below) limit of the geometric mean ratio (0.9412) , [0.8634,1.0260], lies in the FDA endorsed equivalence bounds [0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistical Notes (1): Geometric Mean and Geometric Mean Ratio</title>
      <link>/2012/09/12/statistical-notes-1-geometric-mean-and-geometric-mean-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2012 20:15:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/09/12/statistical-notes-1-geometric-mean-and-geometric-mean-ratio/</guid>
      <description>_Programmers Need to Learn Statistics Or I will Kill Them All –Zed A. Shaw_
 Just read since SAS 9.2, the TTEST procedure also natively supports Equivalence Test by simply adding a TOST option (Two one-sided tests). In a example, TTEST procedure reports a geometric mean as 0.9412, which is the geometric mean of a ratio, TestAUC/RefAUC. It can also be calculated manually by
 proc sql; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; select exp(mean(log(TestAUC/RefAUC))) &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; &amp;ldquo;geometric mean of TestAUC/RefAUC&amp;rdquo; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; from auc; quit;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Life and Personal Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/2012/04/04/digital-life-and-personal-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 20:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/04/04/digital-life-and-personal-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This picture (by newsobserver.com) took from Wake County Library Book Fair in North Carolina Fairground where I also went to pick up some books. 
I was and still is a big book (almost paper books) fan. But when I was standing among the 450,000 used books in the book fair, I felt depressed and reluctantly had an impression: the paper&amp;#160; books will and should go away in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>US Post Beats Menu Cost</title>
      <link>/2012/03/24/us-post-beats-menu-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 01:29:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/03/24/us-post-beats-menu-cost/</guid>
      <description>One of the interesting observations in my first few months in US: there is no price printed in the new mail stamps!
It is interesting because as a former student of economics, I think US Post system did a nice attempt to beat the so called “menu cost” which should honor to Harvard economist Mankiw. Literally the menu cost is the cost of a restaurant to print new menus due to price adjustment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Collection of SAS Macro Repositories</title>
      <link>/2011/11/08/my-collection-of-sas-macro-repositories/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2011 21:41:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/11/08/my-collection-of-sas-macro-repositories/</guid>
      <description>Then I just find that the most effective and safest way to synchronize bookmarks across machines is making them Google searchable, i.e, putting them online.
Followings are my personal collections of SAS macro Repositories (I will keep it update according to new sites reached and your inputs). Most of them are rich, well documented and friendly for navigation and review:
/*\*General**/
1. SAS Macros by Richard DeVenezia****
http://www.devenezia.com/downloads/sas/macros/index.php
Richard is a very active contributor in SAS-L.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS Bloggers In Action(1): Rick Wicklin, SAS/IML and &amp;ldquo;Color Revolution&amp;rdquo;</title>
      <link>/2011/07/17/sas-bloggers-in-action1-rick-wicklin-sas/iml-and-ldquocolor-revolutionrdquo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 16:16:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/07/17/sas-bloggers-in-action1-rick-wicklin-sas/iml-and-ldquocolor-revolutionrdquo/</guid>
      <description>It is well known that the French writer, author of The Three Musketeer, Alexandre Dumas, wrote his master piece of work in different colored papers according to literary genre:
 non-fiction on&amp;#160; rose,
fiction on blue,
poetry on yellow
 The SAS blog writer, author of Statistical Programming with SAS/IML Software, Rick Wicklin of SAS Institute,&amp;#160; also leads a strong “color revolution” in SAS blog community:
In an interesting personal statement, Blogging, Programming, and Johari Windows, Rick summarizes his rich and colorful blogging rhythms according to the above Johari window:&amp;#160;&amp;#160;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recursive Referencing and Binomial Proportion Interval</title>
      <link>/2010/11/03/recursive-referencing-and-binomial-proportion-interval/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Nov 2010 20:47:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/11/03/recursive-referencing-and-binomial-proportion-interval/</guid>
      <description>To understand recursion, one of the most important concepts in programming languages, you could watch the movie, Chris Nolan’s Inception: it is about a dream within a dream within a dream, …and, read two statistical papers by Professor Robert Newcombe, one of the most prolific statisticians:
 Two-sided confidence intervals for the single proportion: comparison of seven methods. 
Newcombe RG, Stat Med , Volume 17 , 8 (April 1998) pp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On three statistical realms</title>
      <link>/2010/10/06/on-three-statistical-realms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2010 11:37:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/10/06/on-three-statistical-realms/</guid>
      <description>Peter Petocz and Anna Reid(2010) grouped three levels of students’ conceptions of statistics:
 Level I:&amp;#160;&amp;#160; focus on techniques Level II:&amp;#160; focus on using data Level III: focus on meaning  I found the three conceptions could be easily interpreted as the three kinds of state of learning and using statistics based on my personal experience:
 State I: focus on techniques—As a student of Economics and (then) Software Engineering, I needed some statistics techniques to support my study on data mining and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>