<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>format on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/format/</link>
    <description>Recent content in format on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 13:06:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/format/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Import .Rdata to SAS, along with Labels</title>
      <link>/2015/05/12/import-.rdata-to-sas-along-with-labels/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 13:06:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2015/05/12/import-.rdata-to-sas-along-with-labels/</guid>
      <description>I didn’t play with SAS/IML for a while. I call it back when I need to read some R format data.
Technically, .Rdata is not a data format. It’s rather a big container to hold bunch of R objects:

In this example, when a .Rdata is loaded, 3 objects are included where ‘data’(the ‘real’ data) and ‘desc’ (data description portion) are of our interests.
SAS/IML offers a nice interface to call R command which can be used to read the R format data:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS Format Viewer and Others (EG)</title>
      <link>/2014/02/06/sas-format-viewer-and-others-eg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 23:28:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2014/02/06/sas-format-viewer-and-others-eg/</guid>
      <description>Today I tried to install a SAS format viewer, one of my favorite SAS AF utilities in a virtual machine, and it came out a bad news and a good news.
The bad news is that the website I used to download the SAS Format Viewer (by Frank Poppe) is no longer accessible(LESSON LEARNED: make an offline copy when you check piece of codes online!).
While the good news is, that a company named BiX just released a free version of (yet another) SAS format viewer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Check? Use SAS Format!</title>
      <link>/2013/02/24/how-to-write-a-check-use-sas-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 21:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/24/how-to-write-a-check-use-sas-format/</guid>
      <description>During my initial stay in US last year, one of the interesting exercises was to write a check. The Arabic numerals (the universal language!) were pretty intuitive while I didn’t feel much comfortable on spelling the face value in words: I never played the game! 
But the good side of this story was, as a SAS programmer and I used a WORDFw. Format:
 data null; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; money=8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great, Open, Vendor-neutral, Platform-independent Data Standards, . . . Yet in PDF Formats</title>
      <link>/2012/12/29/the-great-open-vendor-neutral-platform-independent-data-standards-.-.-.-yet-in-pdf-formats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Dec 2012 17:47:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/29/the-great-open-vendor-neutral-platform-independent-data-standards-.-.-.-yet-in-pdf-formats/</guid>
      <description>You know I mean the CDISC standards including CDASH, SDTM, SEND, ADaM, … and you are right there are few not only in PDF format (ODM, define.xml for example).
Today Jozef (Jos) Aerts from XML4Pharma posted his frustration of copying and pasting metadata from only PDF-formed SDTM-IG 3.1.4.&amp;#160; I hate to complain the volunteer work by the CDISC team but it is worth a discussion, is there any better way to publish CDISC Standards?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract the Version of SAS and OS of a SAS Format or Macro Catalog: A Little Bit of Perl Regular Expression</title>
      <link>/2012/11/25/extract-the-version-of-sas-and-os-of-a-sas-format-or-macro-catalog-a-little-bit-of-perl-regular-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 20:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/25/extract-the-version-of-sas-and-os-of-a-sas-format-or-macro-catalog-a-little-bit-of-perl-regular-expression/</guid>
      <description>SAS Sample 34444(Determine the operating system in which a format catalog was created) posts piece of codes to get the version of SAS and OS of a SAS format catalog. It is useful since a SAS catalog can be only read in the operating systems same to its source machine.
2 cents add to this note:
First, we do not need to write codes to get to know the machine version for a catalog(formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two SAS AF Utilities: LogFilter and Format Viewer</title>
      <link>/2012/10/02/two-sas-af-utilities-logfilter-and-format-viewer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 14:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/10/02/two-sas-af-utilities-logfilter-and-format-viewer/</guid>
      <description>Nice to have (and easy to follow, both tested in Windows 7 with SAS 9.3M1 while they were both written in lower version of SAS):
1. LogFilter: a SAS log checker by rtsl
http://www.ratcliffe.co.uk/rest_logfilt.htm
2. A SAS format viewer by Frank Poppe
http://frank-poppe.xs4all.nl/SAS/edit_format.html</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>