<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graph on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/graph/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graph on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 01:13:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/graph/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Best of SAS: A Personal Nomination 2012</title>
      <link>/2012/12/31/best-of-sas-a-personal-nomination-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2012 01:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/12/31/best-of-sas-a-personal-nomination-2012/</guid>
      <description>There SAS applications/procedures/features were not necessarily available since 2012. This year I paid special attention to them when began to use SAS 9.3. The following notes are&amp;#160; totally my personal endorsement purely based my own experience as a user:
XML File Reading: SAS XML Mapper 
SAS XML Mapper itself is not an elegant tool from software design perspective (an example: I keep multiple versions because the latest version seems not carry out all the functionalities from old ones), but it is best XML file processing tool for SAS programmers like me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Digital Life and Personal Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/2012/04/04/digital-life-and-personal-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2012 20:32:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/04/04/digital-life-and-personal-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>This picture (by newsobserver.com) took from Wake County Library Book Fair in North Carolina Fairground where I also went to pick up some books. 
I was and still is a big book (almost paper books) fan. But when I was standing among the 450,000 used books in the book fair, I felt depressed and reluctantly had an impression: the paper&amp;#160; books will and should go away in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy SAS Graphing!</title>
      <link>/2010/10/17/happy-sas-graphing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Oct 2010 20:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/10/17/happy-sas-graphing/</guid>
      <description>I’m not a R user. Instead, I’m an observer. For example, I love the R Graph Gallery:
 http://addictedtor.free.fr/graphiques/thumbs.php
 As a SAS programmer, I also love Robert Allison&amp;#8216;s SAS/Graph Examples and Michael Friendly&amp;#8216;s SAS Graphic Programs and Macros (the only two SAS graph galleries available on website maintained by users):
 http://robslink.com/SAS/Home.htm
http://www.datavis.ca/sasmac/
 I used to be a casual user of SAS Graph. I’d like to add Graph into my toolbox in the following month: half of it due to the encouragement of the two SAS graph gurus, the other half SAS 9.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FYI: Dashboard using SAS/Graph</title>
      <link>/2009/01/13/fyi-dashboard-using-sas/graph/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2009 15:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/01/13/fyi-dashboard-using-sas/graph/</guid>
      <description>see, http://support.sas.com/kb/26/134.html
 Slider chart indicator:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version  Slider chart dashboard:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version  Bullet graph indicator:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version  Bullet graph dashboard:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version  Dial meter indicator:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version  Dial meter dashboard:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version  Bar chart indicator:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version  Bar chart dashboard:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version  Telesales dashboard:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version  Web marketing analysis dashboard:  SAS program version stored process version portlet version   You would also like, Santa&amp;#8217;s Dashboard:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Santa and SAS Again: Santa&amp;#8217;s Dashboard</title>
      <link>/2008/12/18/santa-and-sas-again-santa#8217s-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2008 09:34:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/18/santa-and-sas-again-santa#8217s-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>(santaDashBoard.png, With permission by Mr. Robert Allison)
Merry Christmas again. SAS marketing staff started up an interesting Christmas campaign on how Santa operates his workshop. Here is another wonderful work about Santa&amp;#8217;s Dashboard, created by SAS senior R&amp;amp;D staff, Robert Allison.
Robert is a master of graphics and visualization. You can view his SAS/Graph examples in the following link:
http://robslink.com/SAS/Home.htm</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>