<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Perl Regular Expression on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/perl-regular-expression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Perl Regular Expression on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 21:59:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/perl-regular-expression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Write a Check? Use SAS Format!</title>
      <link>/2013/02/24/how-to-write-a-check-use-sas-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Feb 2013 21:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2013/02/24/how-to-write-a-check-use-sas-format/</guid>
      <description>During my initial stay in US last year, one of the interesting exercises was to write a check. The Arabic numerals (the universal language!) were pretty intuitive while I didn’t feel much comfortable on spelling the face value in words: I never played the game! 
But the good side of this story was, as a SAS programmer and I used a WORDFw. Format:
 data null; &amp;#160;&amp;#160;&amp;#160; money=8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extract the Version of SAS and OS of a SAS Format or Macro Catalog: A Little Bit of Perl Regular Expression</title>
      <link>/2012/11/25/extract-the-version-of-sas-and-os-of-a-sas-format-or-macro-catalog-a-little-bit-of-perl-regular-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 20:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2012/11/25/extract-the-version-of-sas-and-os-of-a-sas-format-or-macro-catalog-a-little-bit-of-perl-regular-expression/</guid>
      <description>SAS Sample 34444(Determine the operating system in which a format catalog was created) posts piece of codes to get the version of SAS and OS of a SAS format catalog. It is useful since a SAS catalog can be only read in the operating systems same to its source machine.
2 cents add to this note:
First, we do not need to write codes to get to know the machine version for a catalog(formats.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XML and SAS</title>
      <link>/2010/10/07/xml-and-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Oct 2010 11:44:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2010/10/07/xml-and-sas/</guid>
      <description>Last month, I gave a talk, XML: the SAS Approach, in CDISC Interchange China 2010(at the Medical School of Fudan University, Shanghai, 2010-09-15). FDA favors CDISC and HL7, the two XML based standards, and SAS programmers in biopharmaceutical industry&amp;#160; need incorporate the XML technology into their toolboxes. Fortunately, you don’t need to be an XML expert then to play XML in your daily work, and, SAS system DOES offer multiple tools and applications to handle XML files, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>