<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>data mining on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</title>
    <link>/tags/data-mining/</link>
    <description>Recent content in data mining on Jiangtang Hu | 胡江堂</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 22:15:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/data-mining/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Analytical Valley: Big Data and Data Scientists (and SAS Programmers)</title>
      <link>/2011/09/14/an-analytical-valley-big-data-and-data-scientists-and-sas-programmers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2011 22:15:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/09/14/an-analytical-valley-big-data-and-data-scientists-and-sas-programmers/</guid>
      <description>Tom Davenport reported an observation that Silicon Valley is becoming more analytical since companies in the Valley such as Google, Facebook, eBay, LinkedLn all have strong presences in analytics. Besides such predominant companies, I’d also like to add Yahoo to the list although Yahoo is no longer in its peak. Yahoo is the largest sponsor and contributor of Hadoop, an open source framework for distributed processing of so called “big data”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feature Selection: Collections for Self Study</title>
      <link>/2011/01/15/feature-selection-collections-for-self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2011 10:58:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/15/feature-selection-collections-for-self-study/</guid>
      <description>Recently I start to learn the algorithms and applications of feature selection. The term “Feature”, wildly used in machine learning and data mining literatures, simply means “Variable”. In some practices, for example, a neural network model uses a decision tree as input; the tree performs the function of variables selection.
The Arizona State University is maintaining a repository of feature selection, including original documentations, Matlab packages and user guide for the following popular algorithms so far:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decision Trees in SAS Enterprise Miner and SPSS Clementine</title>
      <link>/2011/01/04/decision-trees-in-sas-enterprise-miner-and-spss-clementine/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2011 20:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2011/01/04/decision-trees-in-sas-enterprise-miner-and-spss-clementine/</guid>
      <description>Decision trees are included in SAS Enterprise Miner(EM). The counterpart is SPSS Clementine, which should be called IBM SPSS Modeler for precision after IBM’s acquisition of SPSS.
Recently I read a paper on the comparisons of SAS EM, SPSS Clementine and IBM Intelligent Miner on their decision tree and cluster technology:
 _Decision Tree Induction &amp;amp; Clustering Techniques in SAS Enterprise Miner, SPSS Clementine, and IBM Intelligent Miner – A Comparative Analysis_ by Abdullah M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Run data mining codes following William Potts</title>
      <link>/2009/03/20/run-data-mining-codes-following-william-potts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 11:41:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/03/20/run-data-mining-codes-following-william-potts/</guid>
      <description>FYI: SAS Enterprise Miner and SAS Text Miner Procedures: Reference for SAS 9.1.3, see:   &amp;nbsp;   http://support.sas.com/documentation/onlinedoc/miner/emtmsas913/listing.html   &amp;nbsp;   This entry DOES exist in the SAS Support website, but it can&amp;#8217;t be found by any search engine or documentation tree view. You&amp;#8217;re recommended to download these files immediately due to SAS&amp;#8217;s easy-dead hyperlinks.^-^    &amp;nbsp;   ps.SAS Institute provides no support for the use of Enterprise Miner and Text Miner Procedures when they are invoked directly, outside of the Enterprise Miner graphical user interface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAS User Books and Data Mining Software Comparision: Quick Links</title>
      <link>/2009/02/17/sas-user-books-and-data-mining-software-comparision-quick-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2009 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2009/02/17/sas-user-books-and-data-mining-software-comparision-quick-links/</guid>
      <description> SAS Books Catalog(Jan, 2009) Data Mining Software 2009: Succesul Analyses at Affordable Prices(Nov. 2008, by mayato)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Industry Review: SAS and Teradata Partnership</title>
      <link>/2008/12/19/industry-review-sas-and-teradata-partnership/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2008 10:44:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/19/industry-review-sas-and-teradata-partnership/</guid>
      <description>SAS and Teradata Partnership: Press   Leading Companies See Value in SAS and Teradata Partnership SAS and Teradata Unveil Advantage Program to Bring Powerful In-Database Solutions and Services to Customers SAS and Teradata Enter into Strategic Partnership    In BI industry, the pure players such as SAS, Teradata and Microstrategy, need to demonstrate their indispensable values against the megavendors, IBM (acquired Cognos), SAP (acquired Business Object), Oracle (acquired Hyperion) and Microsoft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Mining in Stock Market</title>
      <link>/2008/12/13/data-mining-in-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 23:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2008/12/13/data-mining-in-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>Data Mining in Stock Market? Is it crazy? or is it just a hopeless try? Every mentor in mathematics and finance educates us that the stock market is too chaotic and sentimental to use mathematical models. Most of all gift rock scientists are concentrated in the study of interest of rates and fixed income securities. It sounds profitable to use mathematical and statistical models to predict the price of stock, but there are little successfull stories.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>